const arr = [{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"What is the drug of choice in cestode infection?","answers":[{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":true},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false}],"id":0},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"What is the gold-standard investigation for typhoid?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true},{"option":"Urinalysis","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow culture","bool":false},{"option":"Splenic biopsy","bool":false}],"id":1},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A child presents to the clinic with fever and convulsions. The child was bitten by a dog 3 months ago. Which of the following samples must be obtained to confirm a diagnosis of rabies?","answers":[{"option":"Cerebrospinal fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Nail clippings","bool":false},{"option":"Stool","bool":false},{"option":"Urine","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false}],"id":2},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following negligences refers to defective hospital care and equipment, incompetent employees, and failure to maintain the standards of care?","answers":[{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Third party negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":true},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":false}],"id":3},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the emergency department with complaints of fever, fatigue, and headache for the past 10 days. He is now experiencing agitation and hallucination, with aggressive behavior. History suggests that he suffered a dog bite 4 weeks ago. On examination, he is found to have excessive salivation, hyperreflexia, and spasticity. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes simplex encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Creutzfeldt-Jacob disease","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":true},{"option":"Psychosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tetanus","bool":false}],"id":4},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old unconscious male is brought to the emergency room with profuse bleeding from the incised wound on his left wrist. Which of the following types of consent will be used to treat this patient?","answers":[{"option":"No need of consent","bool":false},{"option":"Written consent","bool":false},{"option":"Implied consent","bool":true},{"option":"Oral consent","bool":false},{"option":"Expressed consent","bool":false}],"id":5},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"During a police encounter, a dacoit is shot dead. Who will carry out the investigation in this case?","answers":[{"option":"The coroner","bool":false},{"option":"The police","bool":false},{"option":"The magistrate","bool":true},{"option":"Medico-legal officer of the area","bool":false},{"option":"The panchas","bool":false}],"id":6},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A doctor receives 5 cases of cholera together at his private clinic in Lahore. He should report these cases to which of the following authorities?","answers":[{"option":"District nazim","bool":false},{"option":"District police station","bool":false},{"option":"Local police station","bool":false},{"option":"Area magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"District health authorities","bool":true}],"id":7},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 36-year-old woman, with a known case of HIV infection, has a very low CD4 lymphocyte count and was prescribed treatment. She is non-compliant with her medications and now presents with shortness of breath on exertion and hypoxia. Her chest X-ray reveals fine bilateral infiltrates and the computed tomography (CT) scan reports a bilateral ground-glass appearance. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumococcal pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Influenza","bool":false}],"id":8},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A young patient presents to the clinic with complaints of acute watery diarrhea without abdominal pain, along with vomiting. The stool is rice-watery in nature. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Norvovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Amebiasis (E. histolytica)","bool":false}],"id":9},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following antimalarial drugs is effective against the exo-erythrocytic form of malarial parasite?","answers":[{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true}],"id":10},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 15-year-old boy comes into the emergency department. He has had a history of fever for the last 2 weeks, initially, low-grade 100 F, followed by high-grade with severe abdominal pain. His blood culture is done as an outpatient is positive for Salmonella typhi with sensitivity to azithromycin and imipenem-cilastatin. An X-ray of the abdomen, erect and supine, shows gas under the right diaphragm. What is the most common site of gut perforation in enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Stomach perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending colon perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Jejunum perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Duodenal perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Ileal perforation","bool":true}],"id":11},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A doctor is called in sessions court as a witness. During cross-examination, he utters an indecent remark on the defense counsel, which is brought to the knowledge of the judge who gives minimum punishment to the doctor. Which of the following would it be?","answers":[{"option":"Fee of Rs. 10 only","bool":false},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 100 only","bool":false},{"option":"Warning in writing with copy to the employer","bool":false},{"option":"Detaining him in the court till rising of the court for the day","bool":true},{"option":"Fee of Rs. 50 only","bool":false}],"id":12},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A young male develops a high-grade fever intermittent in nature and occurring every 48 hours. Later on, his laboratory report reveals that he has vivax malaria. Which subtype fever does he have?","answers":[{"option":"Quotidian fever","bool":false},{"option":"Quartan fever","bool":false},{"option":"Relapsing fever","bool":false},{"option":"Tertian fever","bool":true},{"option":"Malignant tertian fever","bool":false}],"id":13},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2022","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is an appropriate drug in the treatment of acute enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":true},{"option":"Sulphonamide","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false}],"id":14},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"The present-day societies have high expectations from medical professionals regarding their ideal ethical practice. The broader guidelines can be learned from the subject of medical ethics. What does this subject deal with?","answers":[{"option":"Implied contract and its details","bool":false},{"option":"Research ethics should be made mandatory","bool":false},{"option":"Confidentiality of patient record as an ideal ethical practice","bool":false},{"option":"Moral values to be observed by medical professional in their practice","bool":true},{"option":"Interpersonal relationships are the basic requirement","bool":false}],"id":15},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Infections caused by which organisms are treated with pyrantel pamoate?","answers":[{"option":"Clonorchis sinensis and Trichuris trichuria","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium and Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis and Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum and Wucheria bancrofti","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis and Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":true}],"id":16},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"For which of the following disorders is chloroquine used as an anti-inflammatory drug?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal amebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Babesiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic amebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false}],"id":17},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of these diseases is characterized by the presence of 'Negri bodies'?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":true},{"option":"Measles","bool":false}],"id":18},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which vaccines are given at birth according to the EPI schedule?","answers":[{"option":"Penta + OPV","bool":false},{"option":"OPV + BCG + hep B","bool":true},{"option":"OPV 0 + BCG","bool":false},{"option":"BCG + OPV 1","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumo + BCG","bool":false}],"id":19},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"What is the first-line medication for the treatment of enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Meropenem","bool":false},{"option":"Co-amoxiclav","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true}],"id":20},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 6-year-old child is brought by her mother with the complaint of severe agitation and disturbed sleep at night for the past week. On inquiry, the child admits she has severe perianal itching at night. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":true},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false}],"id":21},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the screening test of choice for HIV in neonates?","answers":[{"option":"HIV PCR","bool":true},{"option":"CD4 count","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":false},{"option":"HIV p24 antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Northern Blot","bool":false}],"id":22},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is given with beta-lactam antibiotics for synergistic effect?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Aminoglycoside","bool":true},{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Macrolide","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporin","bool":false}],"id":23},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 10-year-old child is brought to the pediatric emergency room with severe watery diarrhea for the past 2 days. On inquiry, the mother exclaims her child has been passing large volumes of rice-water colored stools, 10-12 episodes per day. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Adenovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Acute gastroenteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Cholera","bool":true}],"id":24},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 25-year-old male presents to the clinic with complaints of a painless ulcer on the shaft of the penis. He has no symptoms otherwise. Clinical examination reveals rubbery enlargement of bilateral inguinal lymph nodes. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Human papillomavirus","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false}],"id":25},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 2-year-old baby is brought to the clinic with the complaint of loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, the baby is vitally stable with no signs of dehydration. Which of the following treatment options will be offered to this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Zinc suspension 2.5 ml/kg for 10 days","bool":false},{"option":"Ringer's lactate 100ml/kg over 3 hours","bool":false},{"option":"Stop breastfeeding immediately","bool":false},{"option":"Give antibiotic for cholera","bool":false},{"option":"ORS after every loose stool","bool":true}],"id":26},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 5-year-old female child is brought to the clinic with loose stools for the past 4 days. On examination, the child is irritable with skin pinch going back in 3 seconds. No other signs of dehydration are observed. What is the replacement fluid and dosage to be given as per the IMNCI protocol?","answers":[{"option":"75 ml/kg ORS over 4 hour period","bool":true},{"option":"100 ml/kg IV Ringer's lactate every 6 hours","bool":false},{"option":"100-200 ml ORS after every loose stool","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing frequency of breastfeeding with 100-200 ml ORS","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml/kg ORS over 3 hour period","bool":false}],"id":27},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following clinical features is typically the first sign of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Uncontrolled urination","bool":false},{"option":"Trismus","bool":true},{"option":"Reflex spasms","bool":false},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false}],"id":28},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"The lawyer of the defendant calls in a ballistic expert as part of the proceedings of a suspected homicide. Which of the following is not true regarding this type of witness?","answers":[{"option":"Describes what he/she saw","bool":true},{"option":"A doctor may be common or expert witness","bool":false},{"option":"Skilled in foreign law","bool":false},{"option":"Can volunteer a statement","bool":false},{"option":"Draws inference from observations","bool":false}],"id":29},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"What is the correct legal terminology for a verbal statement made by a dying individual in front of a doctor narrating the circumstances leading to his/her death?","answers":[{"option":"Dying deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Dying declaration","bool":true},{"option":"Documentary evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Oral evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Compos mentis","bool":false}],"id":30},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae, when Gram-stained and viewed microscopically, appears as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Gram negative cocci in grape like cluster","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive cocci in grape like cluster","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative rods","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive diplococci","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative diplococci","bool":true}],"id":31},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"SIRS is a life-threatening disease that can lead to multiple organ failure, if not treated immediately. What does it stand for?","answers":[{"option":"It stands for systems involved in infection syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It stands for system inflammation related syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It stands for septicemic inflammation related syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It stands for systemic inflammatory response syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"It stands for systematic infection related syndrome","bool":false}],"id":32},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A young girl is admitted to the hospital with frequent bouts of fever that are associated with rigor and chills. On examination of blood film, crescent banana-shaped structures are seen. Her urine turns black on exposure to air. Which of the following organisms is the cause of the patient's symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue virus","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}],"id":33},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"What is the treatment for acute typhoid fever?","answers":[{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"Cefotaxime","bool":false},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false}],"id":34},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"What is the treatment of choice for hydatid disease?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true}],"id":35},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In a nearby daycare center, a group of children develops severe perianal itching and pruritis. Their mothers also identify pumpkin seed-like structures in children's stools. Which of the following organisms is the most likely cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false},{"option":"Hook worm","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":true}],"id":36},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 68-year-old male presents to the emergency room with complaints of diarrhea, vomiting, and abdominal pain. History suggests that he is immunocompromised and suffering from prostate carcinoma for the past 6 years. His laboratory investigations reveal low hemoglobin, raised erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), and decreased total leukocyte count (TLC). His diagnosis is made by detecting oocysts in fecal smear with the help of a modified Kinyoun acid-fast stain. Which of the following organisms is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":true},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba dispar","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false}],"id":37},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is/are mediators of hypotension?","answers":[{"option":"C5a","bool":false},{"option":"Hageman factor","bool":false},{"option":"Bradykinin and nitric oxide","bool":true},{"option":"C3a","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":false}],"id":38},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"When are leading questions asked?","answers":[{"option":"When an expert has been called","bool":false},{"option":"During examination-in-chief","bool":false},{"option":"When the judge wishes to ask questions","bool":false},{"option":"A hostile witness is being questioned","bool":true},{"option":"When the witness is of unsound mind","bool":false}],"id":39},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 45-year-old male presents to the clinic with a palpable mass in the right hypochondrium. A complete blood count shows eosinophilia and a chest X-ray shows calcification below the right diaphragm. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Amoebic liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocellular carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pyogenic liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Metastases due to malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid liver disease with calcification","bool":true}],"id":40},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following parasites may cause rectal prolapse in children and has barrel-shaped eggs on microscopic analysis?","answers":[{"option":"Histoplasma capsulatum","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiuria","bool":true},{"option":"Ancyclostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":false},{"option":"Loa Loa","bool":false}],"id":41},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Breakbone fever is another name for which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":false},{"option":"Congo fever","bool":false},{"option":"Ebola fever","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Lassa fever","bool":false}],"id":42},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following bacteria is known to be a usual cause of bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":true}],"id":43},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 4-year-old child is brought to the clinic with a history of fever and right knee swelling for the past one week. For the last month, he has been having dysuria on and off and urethral discharge. On examination, in addition to signs of the acute arthritis of the right knee, there is a pustular rash on his leg. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Disseminated Neisseria gonorrhoeae infection","bool":true},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis infection","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex infection","bool":false},{"option":"Syphilis","bool":false}],"id":44},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"What is the primary reason for the increasing typhoid disease burden in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Drug resistance","bool":true},{"option":"Lack of skilled professionals","bool":false},{"option":"Inaccessibility of healthcare facilities","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccine hesitancy","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of awareness of hygiene practices","bool":false}],"id":45},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department by his parents with a complaint of loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, the child is found to be active with no visible signs of dehydration. What is the management for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"ORS 100-200ml after each loose motion","bool":true},{"option":"I/V ringer lactate","bool":false},{"option":"I/V normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"No fluids","bool":false},{"option":"Mineral water","bool":false}],"id":46},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 28-year-old male comes to the emergency room with complaints of rising fever for the past 4 days, which was initially low grade and has become high grade. He also complains of generalized weakness and abdominal pain. On general examinations, the vitals are; blood pressure: 100/60 mm Hg, pulse: 64 beats per minute, temperature:  103 °F, respiratory rate: 22 breaths per minute. The systemic examination is unremarkable. What is the patient most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Brucellosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true}],"id":47},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the mediator responsible for causing fever in systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS)?","answers":[{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":true},{"option":"Bradykinin","bool":false},{"option":"Hageman factor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":48},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"All the travelers who are exposed to the risk of yellow fever or pass through the endemic zones of yellow fever should have a valid vaccination card for yellow fever before they enter a country.  If any of them fails to possess the card, which of the following should be done?","answers":[{"option":"Treated","bool":false},{"option":"Kept in isolation","bool":false},{"option":"Kept in quarantine","bool":true},{"option":"Immunized","bool":false},{"option":"Sent back","bool":false}],"id":49},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"An 18-year-old boy, who has migrated from Quetta to Karachi, presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, abdominal pain, lethargy, and reduced appetite since the past week. History suggests that he is working at a tandoor (roti) shop for the last 3 months and lives in an unhygienic environment. He drinks tap water. On examination, a faint, salmon-colored, maculopapular rash is noticed on his trunk. Apart from a complete blood count (CBC), what is the next most appropriate test to diagnose his illness?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Urine for culture and sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Stool for ova and parasite","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis A and E antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Blood for culture and sensitivity","bool":true}],"id":50},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following refers to the restriction of the movement of a sick person in order to stop the spread of certain diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Rehabilitation","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial prevention","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary prevention","bool":false},{"option":"Quarantine","bool":false},{"option":"Isolation","bool":true}],"id":51},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 12-year-old boy presents to the emergency room with complaints of fever and abdominal cramps, followed by diarrhea.  The diarrhea was initially watery but now contains blood and mucus. Which organism is the cause of diarrhea and dysentery?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella spp","bool":true},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}],"id":52},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"In the case of the transfer of malaria protozoa by the mosquito, which of the following forms is transferred?","answers":[{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Gametocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Schizonts","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":true}],"id":53},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"What is an unusual, more than expected occurrence of a disease or any event related to health, in a community, called?","answers":[{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":true},{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperendemic","bool":false}],"id":54},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following drugs inhibits the microtubule formation in roundworm, pinworm, and hookworm infections and can eradicate worm infestation?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Thiabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false}],"id":55},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 24-year-old farmer comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of difficulty in opening his mouth. He also has a small wound in the heel of his right foot. On examination, generalized body stiffness is found. He is rushed to the emergency room for further evaluation of suspected tetanus. Which of the following is an important step in the management of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Give intravenous metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Give prophylactic heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Administer adsorbed tetanus toxoid (TT)","bool":false},{"option":"Perform endotracheal intubation","bool":false},{"option":"Administer human tetanus immunoglobulin (HTIG)","bool":true}],"id":56},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A young patient comes to the clinic with a complaint of abdominal pain for 2 days, accompanied by a fever for the past one day. Laboratory results show increased total leukocyte count (TLC) and raised erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR). The doctor suspects the acute inflammation of the intestine. Which of the following is responsible for his symptoms and acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Lipoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-24","bool":false},{"option":"Histamine","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-23","bool":false},{"option":"Interlukin-1","bool":true}],"id":57},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of diarrhea. On examination, he is seen to have rectal prolapse. His stool analysis shows barrel-shaped eggs with plugs at each end. Which one of the following nematodes is most likely to be involved?","answers":[{"option":"Loa loa","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella","bool":false}],"id":58},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Schüffner’s dots are the intracytoplasmic granules found, within infected red cells, due to an infection with which of the following plasmodium species?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false}],"id":59},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Among all the types of leprosy, which of the following has a good prognosis and may even heal itself?","answers":[{"option":"Borderline tuberculoid","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true}],"id":60},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 16-year-old male presents with a complaint of high-grade fever with chills and rigors for five days along with severe body aches and pains. On peripheral examination, the patient is febrile. On systemic examination, no significant finding was found except his petechial rashes all over the extremities. What would the most likely diagnosis be?","answers":[{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false}],"id":61},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A patient presents with complaints of fever and body ache for the past two days. What is the best initial test for the diagnosis of dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) and c-reactive protein (CRP) tests","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue nonstructural protein 1 (NS1) test","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue serology","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function tests","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false}],"id":62},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the most sensitive test for diagnosis of liver hydatid cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) of the abdomen","bool":true},{"option":"Serology","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of the abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Fine needle aspiration (FNA)","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound of the abdomen","bool":false}],"id":63},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following organisms causes diarrheal disease in almost 100% of the children by the age of five years?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":true},{"option":"Candida","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false}],"id":64},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A certain tapeworm uses two elongated sucking grooves to attach to the intestinal wall. It may lead to vitamin B-12 deficiency, resulting in megaloblastic anemia. Which of the following worms is this?","answers":[{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":true},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false}],"id":65},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following drug is the preferable treatment in the case of neurocysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazaole","bool":false}],"id":66},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient complains of having recurrent malarial infection after recovering from it once, caused by Plasmodium ovale and Plasmodium vivax. Which form of these Plasmodium species is responsible for the relapses?","answers":[{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Gametozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Metacryptozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":false}],"id":67},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A convict is called numerous times to attend a trial in court, but he fails to appear. Ultimately the court orders a summons to be put outside his house. Which of the following describes a summons?","answers":[{"option":"A warrant to arrest the person and present them in the court","bool":false},{"option":"Letter to a person to appear in court for evidence or any other reason","bool":true},{"option":"A letter that can only issued by the magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"A rectangular scripture to call upon an entity for assistance","bool":false},{"option":"A fee tendered to cover court expenses","bool":false}],"id":68},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following drugs acts by increasing the GABA activity?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false}],"id":69},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Leaving gauze in abdominal surgery comes under which negligence?","answers":[{"option":"Civil negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":true},{"option":"3rd party negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate misconduct","bool":false},{"option":"Corporate negligence","bool":false}],"id":70},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 6-year-old child took his father's pistol to show to his friends but the pistol accidentally went off. One of his friends got injured. Under the law, the child is considered as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Guilty","bool":false},{"option":"Unfit to plead","bool":false},{"option":"Not sane","bool":false},{"option":"Not criminally responsible","bool":true},{"option":"Diminished responsible","bool":false}],"id":71},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old diabetic patient presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever associated with rigor and chills and increased frequency of urine. There are no other significant findings. What is the most probable cause?","answers":[{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Viral fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false}],"id":72},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient in the hospital was on the ventilator and got treated for an illness with clindamycin, ethambutol, and some other antibiotics. He then got extubated and was started on meropenem 10 days ago. Two days ago he presented with watery diarrhea suggesting a C. difficile infection. How will this condition be managed?","answers":[{"option":"IV vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Stop all antibiotics and send stool sample for ova and parasite","bool":false},{"option":"Stop meropenem and give oral metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Oral vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"IV metronidazole","bool":false}],"id":73},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Zieman dots with basket forms and occasional band forms of plasmodium are seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}],"id":74},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"At what CD4+ count of a patient with human immunodeficiency virus do AIDS-defining illnesses emerge?","answers":[{"option":"< 50 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 200 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":true},{"option":"< 150 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 100 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"< 250 CD4+ cells/mm3","bool":false}],"id":75},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 25-year-old male presented with fever and abdominal pain. His illness started with low-grade fever and decreased appetite. He has been unwell for the past 7 days and has per rectal bleeding for the last 2 days. Initially, he took per ciprofloxacin for 3 days followed by oral cefixime and azithromycin for 4 days. He was started on intravenous (IV) ceftriaxone. What is the most appropriate diagnostic test?","answers":[{"option":"Stool culture","bool":true},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow culture","bool":false},{"option":"Rectal swab for culture","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood picture with peripheral film","bool":false}],"id":76},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"The Pakistan Medical and Dental Council found a medical practitioner involved in dichotomy. He is guilty of which of the following kind of offense?","answers":[{"option":"Perjury","bool":false},{"option":"Civil malpraxix","bool":false},{"option":"Criminal negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Professional misconduct","bool":true},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false}],"id":77},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"For which of these organisms is pyrantel pamoate not effective?","answers":[{"option":"Pinworm","bool":false},{"option":"Whipworm","bool":true},{"option":"Roundworm","bool":false},{"option":"Hookworm","bool":false},{"option":"All nematodes","bool":false}],"id":78},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these drugs is useful for the prevention of retrograde intestinal cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ketoconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":true},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}],"id":79},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these drugs is used to treat the exoerythrocytic stage of malarial parasite?","answers":[{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemether","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquinine","bool":false},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false}],"id":80},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the most common side effect of penicillin?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Paraeshtesias","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity reactions","bool":true},{"option":"Rhabdomyolysis","bool":false}],"id":81},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these drugs is penicillinase-resistant?","answers":[{"option":"Methicillin","bool":true},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin V","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin G","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false}],"id":82},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these methods is not useful in the management of Clostridium difficile infections?","answers":[{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Isolation of the patient","bool":false},{"option":"IV vancomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Removal of offending agent","bool":false},{"option":"Immunoglobulins","bool":false}],"id":83},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A 21-year-old male is being treated for malaria with quinine, following which he experiences a blackish discoloration of his urine. What is this complication called?","answers":[{"option":"Alkaptonuria","bool":false},{"option":"Blackwater fever","bool":true},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Rhabdomyolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":false}],"id":84},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the meaning of the term 'Voire dire'?","answers":[{"option":"To confess murder","bool":false},{"option":"To take judgement","bool":false},{"option":"To accuse someone","bool":false},{"option":"To claim mental illness","bool":false},{"option":"To take oath","bool":true},{"option":"To pass judgment","bool":false}],"id":85},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A 7-year-old girl presents to the office with a complaint of fever for the last 10 days. She also developed a red, spotty rash over her abdomen 2 days ago. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Drug reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":true}],"id":86},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the best test for the diagnosis of enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Clinical","bool":false},{"option":"PCR assay","bool":false},{"option":"Throat swab","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true},{"option":"Stool culture","bool":false}],"id":87},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"In which of the following courts does failure to respond to summons lead to punishment?","answers":[{"option":"Supreme court","bool":false},{"option":"High court","bool":false},{"option":"All courts","bool":true},{"option":"Civil court","bool":false},{"option":"Lower court","bool":false}],"id":88},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What are 'leading' questions?","answers":[{"option":"An open-ended question","bool":false},{"option":"The last question","bool":false},{"option":"A question which is relevant to the case","bool":false},{"option":"A question which directly or indirectly suggests its own answer","bool":true},{"option":"A question which follows an opening question","bool":false}],"id":89},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What does 'Risos sardonicus' refer to?","answers":[{"option":"Established tetanus","bool":true},{"option":"Myasthenia gravis","bool":false},{"option":"Lockjaw","bool":false},{"option":"Botulism","bool":false},{"option":"Tetany","bool":false}],"id":90},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A 19-year-old man presents with right hypochondrial pain and fever for the last 5 days. He also mentions having a few episodes of bloody diarrhea one month ago. What is the most conclusive step in establishing the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Serum antibodies","bool":true},{"option":"Abdominal CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"Liver function tests","bool":false},{"option":"Stool O&P","bool":false}],"id":91},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these drugs is not a nucleotide reverse transcriptase inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Delavirdine","bool":true},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Didanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false}],"id":92},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Intake of which of the following drugs causes a Mazzotti-like reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}],"id":93},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is used in the treatment of filariasis?","answers":[{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":true},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}],"id":94},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following drugs acts on the nicotinic receptor?","answers":[{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Piperazine","bool":true},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false}],"id":95},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is given in Wuchereria bancrofti?","answers":[{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}],"id":96},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is graze is synonymous to?","answers":[{"option":"Cut","bool":false},{"option":"Contact abrasion","bool":false},{"option":"Friction burn","bool":true},{"option":"Scratch","bool":false},{"option":"Laceration","bool":false}],"id":97},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the timeframe between the vaccine and booster dose for an injectable typhoid vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"5 years","bool":false},{"option":"3 years","bool":false},{"option":"2 years","bool":true},{"option":"6 years","bool":false},{"option":"4 years","bool":false}],"id":98},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A 7-year-old child has had 6 to 8 small volume stools daily for the last 3 days. The stools do not contain any blood or mucus. On examination, no signs of dehydration are noticed. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Campylobacter infection","bool":false},{"option":"Shigellosis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Amebiasis","bool":false}],"id":99},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the most common pulmonary disorder in an AIDS patient?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumocystis infection","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":true}],"id":100},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the mode of action of dapsone?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial transcription","bool":false},{"option":"Lysis of bacterial cell walls","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial protein synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial folate synthesis","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of bacterial topoisomerases","bool":false}],"id":101},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A 31-year-old female presents with a painless skin rash behind her right ear. On examination, it is a patch-like hypopigmented area with reduced sensation and well-demarcated borders. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma of the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Skin burn","bool":false},{"option":"Neurofibromatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false}],"id":102},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which type of immunity is observed in tuberculoid leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Natural immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Humoral immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Passive immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Skin barrier","bool":false},{"option":"Cell mediated immunity","bool":true}],"id":103},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the route of administration for the measles vaccine?","answers":[{"option":"Oral","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous","bool":true},{"option":"Sublingual","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous","bool":false},{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":false}],"id":104},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"In which of the following forms of asphyxia are Tardieu spots not seen?","answers":[{"option":"Drowning","bool":true},{"option":"Choking","bool":false},{"option":"Throttling","bool":false},{"option":"Hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Smothering","bool":false}],"id":105},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which organism is responsible for leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium avium","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium bovis","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium intracellulare","bool":false}],"id":106},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"How many serotypes of dengue virus exist?","answers":[{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":true},{"option":"10","bool":false},{"option":"8","bool":false}],"id":107},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the mode of transmission for dengue virus?","answers":[{"option":"Feco-oral","bool":false},{"option":"Droplet","bool":false},{"option":"Vector","bool":true},{"option":"Contact","bool":false},{"option":"Airborne","bool":false}],"id":108},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A 40-year-old farmer is brought to the emergency after collapsing in his home. After regaining consciousness, he complains of right hypochondrial pain and on imaging, calcified cysts are observed in his liver. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pyogenic liver abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Colorectal metastases","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic amebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid cyst","bool":true}],"id":109},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the best confirmatory test for hydatid cyst disease?","answers":[{"option":"Cysts on ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Positive serology for the organism","bool":false},{"option":"Daughter cysts on CT scan","bool":true},{"option":"Calcifications on X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Daughter cysts on ultrasound","bool":false}],"id":110},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following statements regarding primary HIV is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Fever with rash is one of the clinical features","bool":false},{"option":"Usually manifests 3 months after exposure","bool":true},{"option":"70-80 percent of cases are symptomatic","bool":false},{"option":"Fall in CD4 count to 300-400/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"High viral RNA loads are detected","bool":false}],"id":111},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the route of administration of enfuvirtide?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous","bool":false},{"option":"Oral","bool":false},{"option":"Subcutaneous","bool":true},{"option":"Intramuscular","bool":false},{"option":"Dermal","bool":false}],"id":112},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which drug acts by inhibiting ADP phosphorylation?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":true},{"option":"lvermectin","bool":false}],"id":113},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is thanatology?","answers":[{"option":"Study of food chemistry","bool":false},{"option":"Study of jail architecture","bool":false},{"option":"Study of the phenomena of death","bool":true},{"option":"Study of plants","bool":false},{"option":"Study of life","bool":false}],"id":114},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following causes typhoid fever?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":true},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Rickettsia typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Rickettsia prowazekii","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}],"id":115},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the maximum fine that can be set by a 1st class magistrate?","answers":[{"option":"100 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"5,000 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"1,50,000 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"1,000 Rs","bool":false},{"option":"15,000 Rs","bool":true}],"id":116},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not a mode of transmission of HIV?","answers":[{"option":"Blood transfer","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal-fetal transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Sexual transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Needle sharing","bool":false},{"option":"Insect transmission","bool":true}],"id":117},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What causes shingles?","answers":[{"option":"Human herpesvirus 8","bool":false},{"option":"Epstein–Barr virus","bool":false},{"option":"Varicella-zoster virus","bool":true},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false}],"id":118},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"How many trophozoites arise during the excystation of Giardia lamblia?","answers":[{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":true},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"4","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false}],"id":119},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is a proinflammatory mediator?","answers":[{"option":"IL-1","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"TH2 cytokines","bool":false},{"option":"IL-10","bool":false},{"option":"TGF-β","bool":false}],"id":120},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the duration of treatment for leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"2 months","bool":false},{"option":"36 months","bool":false},{"option":"12 months","bool":true},{"option":"2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2 days","bool":false}],"id":121},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What does the respiratory burst in acute inflammation help in?","answers":[{"option":"Increase breathing rate","bool":false},{"option":"Generate H₂O","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease breathing rate","bool":false},{"option":"Produce reactive oxygen species","bool":true},{"option":"Protect DNA","bool":false}],"id":122},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is released by dead bacteria that can cause symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Endotoxins","bool":true},{"option":"Virions","bool":false},{"option":"Exotoxins","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mitochondrial enzymes","bool":false}],"id":123},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What are p17, p24, and p55 in HIV?","answers":[{"option":"Phospholipids","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfatides","bool":false},{"option":"Glycoproteins","bool":true},{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclins","bool":false}],"id":124},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which one of these is not a feature of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Dysphagia","bool":false},{"option":"Altered mental status","bool":true},{"option":"Board like abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false}],"id":125},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What form of plasmodium parasite is taken in by the mosquitoes when they bite humans?","answers":[{"option":"Gametocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Ameboid form","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Schizont","bool":false}],"id":126},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the chemical makeup of the tetanus toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Peptide","bool":true},{"option":"Carbohydrate","bool":false},{"option":"Exotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Multigenic","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxin","bool":false}],"id":127},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the antibiotic of choice for established tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Levofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfamethoxazole","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin G","bool":true},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false}],"id":128},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the confirmatory test for HIV?","answers":[{"option":"T-lymphocyte subset assay","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid test","bool":false},{"option":"Western blot","bool":true},{"option":"Simple test","bool":false}],"id":129},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the vector for the spread of dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Deer fly","bool":false},{"option":"Tsetse fly","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes mosquito","bool":true},{"option":"Dermacentor tick","bool":false}],"id":130},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the earliest sign of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Opisthotonus","bool":false},{"option":"Board like abdominal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Risus sardonicus","bool":false},{"option":"Violent spasms","bool":false},{"option":"Lockjaw","bool":true}],"id":131},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the vector for the spread of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Deer fly","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":true},{"option":"Tsetse fly","bool":false},{"option":"Dermacentor tick","bool":false}],"id":132},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the percentage positivity in hydatid cyst disease serology?","answers":[{"option":"20%","bool":false},{"option":"100%","bool":false},{"option":"5-10%","bool":false},{"option":"70%","bool":false},{"option":"80%","bool":true}],"id":133},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the mode of transmission of trichinosis?","answers":[{"option":"Eating undercooked meat","bool":true},{"option":"Drinking contaminated water","bool":false},{"option":"Walking barefoot on sand","bool":false},{"option":"Mosquito bite","bool":false},{"option":"Eating food contaminated with fecal material","bool":false}],"id":134},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these cephalosporins is 4th generation?","answers":[{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Cefazolin","bool":false},{"option":"Cefoxitin","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftazidime","bool":false},{"option":"Cefepime","bool":true}],"id":135},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which one of these is a diagnostic feature of Echinococcal infection?","answers":[{"option":"Skin rash","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic spaces in the brain","bool":false},{"option":"Brood capsules","bool":true},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Flask-shaped colonic ulcer","bool":false}],"id":136},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these organisms contain 'endotoxin'?","answers":[{"option":"Protozoa","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"Viruses","bool":false},{"option":"Acid fast bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive bacteria","bool":false}],"id":137},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which type of vaccine is used for chickenpox?","answers":[{"option":"Killed vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Subunit vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoid vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivated vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Live attenuated vaccine","bool":true}],"id":138},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"How would a western blot test be deemed positive?","answers":[{"option":"Minimum 7 bands present","bool":false},{"option":"Minimum 2 bands present","bool":false},{"option":"Minimum 3 bands present","bool":true},{"option":"No bands present","bool":false},{"option":"Maximum 2 bands present","bool":false}],"id":139},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which drug that is used to treat leparomatous leprosy also has an anti-inflammatory effect?","answers":[{"option":"Ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":true},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Minocycline","bool":false}],"id":140},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which arachidonic acid metabolite is mainly responsible for leukocyte adhesion?","answers":[{"option":"Prostacyclin","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene B4","bool":true},{"option":"Leukotriene D4","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene C4","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene E4","bool":false}],"id":141},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following courts can give a death sentence?","answers":[{"option":"Section 30 magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"3rd class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"1st class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"2nd class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"Sessions court","bool":true}],"id":142},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is a dying declaration?","answers":[{"option":"A person's statement made just before his death, relating to the cause of death","bool":true},{"option":"An observation of certain facts from which an inference can be concluded","bool":false},{"option":"A statement taken on oath before magistrate in the presence of the accused and his lawyer","bool":false},{"option":"A document produced for the inspection of court","bool":false},{"option":"A statement on oath made by a witness in a judicial proceeding","bool":false}],"id":143},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is a dying deposition?","answers":[{"option":"An observation of certain facts from which an inference can be concluded","bool":false},{"option":"A statement on oath made by a witness in a judicial proceeding","bool":false},{"option":"A person's statement made just before his death, relating to the cause of death","bool":false},{"option":"A document produced for the inspection of court","bool":false},{"option":"A statement taken on oath before magistrate in the presence of the accused and his lawyer","bool":true}],"id":144},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"How is leprosy transmitted?","answers":[{"option":"Airborne droplets","bool":false},{"option":"Vector transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Genetically","bool":false},{"option":"Transplacentally","bool":false},{"option":"Contact with nasal secretions","bool":true}],"id":145},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"In which of the following conditions are nerves thickened?","answers":[{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false}],"id":146},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is a hostile witness?","answers":[{"option":"A well qualified and trained witness that can draw conclusions from facts observed by him and others","bool":false},{"option":"A witness who turned hostile against the party that called him, making statements contradictory to facts","bool":true},{"option":"A witness who could not show up to court","bool":false},{"option":"A witness with a background in martial arts","bool":false},{"option":"A witness who can testify only the facts observed by him","bool":false}],"id":147},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not present in granulomas?","answers":[{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":true},{"option":"Langhans giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Caseation","bool":false}],"id":148},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is not present in oral rehydration therapy (ORS)?","answers":[{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Water","bool":false}],"id":149},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Where does the ookinete of the malarial parasite grow?","answers":[{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mosquito stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Midgut wall","bool":true},{"option":"Liver","bool":false}],"id":150},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Clostridium difficile is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Constipation","bool":false},{"option":"Erythema nodosum","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomembranous colitis","bool":true},{"option":"Brain abscesses","bool":false}],"id":151},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the external incubation period for dengue?","answers":[{"option":"1 month","bool":false},{"option":"10 days","bool":true},{"option":"3 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2 days","bool":false},{"option":"5 hours","bool":false}],"id":152},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS) is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased respiratory rate","bool":false},{"option":">10% band forms","bool":true},{"option":"4,000 > WBC > 12,000 cells/mm3","bool":false},{"option":"Temperatue 37°C","bool":false},{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false}],"id":153},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is true regarding leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Bacilli are seen in hypersensitivity reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in brain nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in tuberculoid reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in gut","bool":false},{"option":"Bacilli are seen in skin allergy reaction","bool":true}],"id":154},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Where are organisms of cutaneous Leishmaniasis seen?","answers":[{"option":"Area of bite of sandfly","bool":true},{"option":"Skin of palms","bool":false},{"option":"Area close to sandfly bite","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Skin of soles","bool":false}],"id":155},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What would the blood smear of a patient with malaria show?","answers":[{"option":"Square bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent shaped bodies","bool":true},{"option":"Granular bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Bilobar bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Multilobar bodies","bool":false}],"id":156},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is dysentery?","answers":[{"option":"Mucous lined stool","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding per-rectal only","bool":false},{"option":"Occult blood in stool","bool":false},{"option":"Visibly bloody stool","bool":true},{"option":"Watery stool","bool":false}],"id":157},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the incubation period for leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Few years","bool":true},{"option":"Few weeks","bool":false},{"option":"Few hours","bool":false},{"option":"Few days","bool":false},{"option":"Few months","bool":false}],"id":158},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of Vibrio cholerae?","answers":[{"option":"Actin polymerization","bool":false},{"option":"Gal-gal pili bind to bladder mucosa","bool":false},{"option":"Ferments lactose","bool":false},{"option":"Produce protease","bool":false},{"option":"ADP ribosylation of Gs protein","bool":true}],"id":159},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is praziquantel ineffective against?","answers":[{"option":"Trematodes","bool":false},{"option":"Clonorchis sinensis","bool":false},{"option":"Nematodes","bool":true},{"option":"Blood flukes","bool":false},{"option":"Paragonimus westermani","bool":false}],"id":160},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice for onchocerciasis?","answers":[{"option":"Bithional","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Triclabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":true}],"id":161},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice for filariasis?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Bithional","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Triclabendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":true}],"id":162},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following courts can grant an amnesty of the death sentence?","answers":[{"option":"2nd class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"High court","bool":true},{"option":"Sessions court","bool":false},{"option":"1st class magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"3rd class magistrate","bool":false}],"id":163},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of the following is the earliest clinical symptom of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Opisthotonos","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory distress","bool":false},{"option":"Uncontrolled urination","bool":false},{"option":"Neck stiffness","bool":false},{"option":"Lockjaw","bool":true}],"id":164},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which cells secrete histamine during acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"B-lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":true},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":false},{"option":"T-lymphocytes","bool":false}],"id":165},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What intravenous drugs should be given as the first choice, following fluid resuscitation, in sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenaline","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Noradrenaline","bool":true}],"id":166},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these cells are affected by HIV in the intestinal mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Kupffer cells","bool":false},{"option":"Dust cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true}],"id":167},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which antibodies are formed in syphilis?","answers":[{"option":"Anti nuclear antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Reagin","bool":true},{"option":"Anti Smith antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti dsDNA antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti mitochondrial antibodies","bool":false}],"id":168},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which inotropic agent is given in cardiogenic shock?","answers":[{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Dobutamine","bool":true},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenoxybenzamine","bool":false}],"id":169},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"What is the movement of leukocytes towards an infected tissue called?","answers":[{"option":"Chemotaxis","bool":true},{"option":"Opsonization","bool":false},{"option":"Migration","bool":false},{"option":"Tumbling motility","bool":false},{"option":"Phagocytosis","bool":false}],"id":170},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"How long does it take for antibodies to appear after HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"30 days","bool":false},{"option":"6 days","bool":false},{"option":"3 days","bool":false},{"option":"60-90 days","bool":false},{"option":"10-14 days","bool":true}],"id":171},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"Which of these is not an indication for antiviral therapy for chickenpox infections?","answers":[{"option":"Uncomplicated chickenpox in children","bool":true},{"option":"Chickenpox in immunocompromised patients regardless of duration","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox in pregnant women regardless of duration","bool":false},{"option":"Complicated chickenpox regardless of duration","bool":false},{"option":"Uncomplicated chickenpox presenting within 24-48 hours","bool":false}],"id":172},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2017"],"question":"A diabetic woman came to the clinic with the complaint of vaginal itch. Which of the following is the most likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Human papilloma virus","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Eczema","bool":false}],"id":173},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the following organisms is the vector for the dengue virus?","answers":[{"option":"Aedes mosquito","bool":true},{"option":"Culex mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Blackfly","bool":false},{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Tsetse fly","bool":false}],"id":174},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the reason for relapsing fever in cases of malaria by Plasmodium vivax and Plasmodium ovale infection?","answers":[{"option":"Trophozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Schizonts","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Sigent-ring cells","bool":false}],"id":175},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of fluoroquinolones?","answers":[{"option":"Disruption of folic acid metabolism","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibiting cell wall synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"DNA gyrase inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of protein synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of RNA polymerase enzyme","bool":false}],"id":176},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Cheese-like discharge is a characteristic of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV","bool":false},{"option":"Candida vaginitis","bool":true},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false}],"id":177},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 4-year-old child is brought to the clinic with a complaint of diarrhea for the past 4 days. On examination, the child is irritable and has sunken eyes. What is the appropriate classification according to IMNCI protocol?","answers":[{"option":"Mild dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"No dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Severe dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Moderate dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Some dehydration","bool":true}],"id":178},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the etiologic agent for enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Paratyphoid virus","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":true},{"option":"Giardia","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter","bool":false}],"id":179},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the incubation period of the causative agent of typhoid fever?","answers":[{"option":"10-14 days","bool":true},{"option":"14-21 days","bool":false},{"option":"2-4 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"20-40 days","bool":false},{"option":"24-48 hours","bool":false}],"id":180},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the below-enlisted opportunistic infections is typically seen in HIV infection with a CD4 count of fewer than 100 cells/mm3?","answers":[{"option":"Oropharyngeal candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral toxoplasmosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes zoster","bool":false},{"option":"Kaposi's sarcoma","bool":false}],"id":181},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"HIV-infected patients with a CD4 count below 500 cells/mm3 are predisposed to which of the following opportunistic pathogens?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium avium complex (MAC)","bool":false},{"option":"Oral hairy leukoplakia","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral toxoplasmosis","bool":false}],"id":182},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the incubation period of Mycobacterium leprae?","answers":[{"option":"14-21 days","bool":false},{"option":"1-2 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"2-4 months","bool":false},{"option":"Several years","bool":true},{"option":"6-9 months","bool":false}],"id":183},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 30-year-old man sustained a bat bite to his arm during a camping trip. He presents to a medical facility 12 hours later and is clinically asymptomatic. What postexposure prophylaxis should be given to this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Rabies toxoid only","bool":false},{"option":"No immunization required","bool":false},{"option":"Active and passive immunity both","bool":true},{"option":"Active immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Passive immunity","bool":false}],"id":184},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the first-line drug for the treatment of mucocutaneous leishmaniasis?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium stibogluconate","bool":true},{"option":"Pentamidine","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Paramomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Amphotericin B","bool":false}],"id":185},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Cerebral malaria is typically caused by which species of the protozoan?","answers":[{"option":"Vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Falciparum","bool":true}],"id":186},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"The causative agent for enteric fever may remain latent in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Gall bladder","bool":true},{"option":"Peyer's patches","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsal root ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Cecum","bool":false},{"option":"Small intestine","bool":false}],"id":187},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A young female is brought to the emergency room with severe abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting for the past 2 hours. She had a meal consisting of rice and curry at a local restaurant 3 hours prior to the onset of her symptoms. What is the likely etiologic agent?","answers":[{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillus cereus","bool":true},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false}],"id":188},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the most common cause of diarrhea in children?","answers":[{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Reovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":true}],"id":189},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A severe outbreak of bloody diarrhea is seen in a psychiatric hospital within the past 1 week. What is the most common agent implicated in such cases?","answers":[{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillus cereus","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella species","bool":true}],"id":190},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which antiretroviral drug is associated with hematological abnormalities?","answers":[{"option":"Didanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Indinavir","bool":false},{"option":"Raltegravir","bool":false},{"option":"Efavirenz","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":true}],"id":191},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of the drug clofazimine?","answers":[{"option":"Folate synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"DNA damage","bool":true},{"option":"Cell wall synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Protein synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Cell membrane damage","bool":false}],"id":192},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 34-year-old male, farmer by profession presents to the outpatient clinic with vague right-sided abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting. Laboratory and radiological workups reveal hydatid cyst disease of the liver. This is his second recurrence in 2 years. What is the treatment for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral albendazole for 30 days","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false},{"option":"PAIR therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Percutaneous drainage","bool":false},{"option":"Watch and wait","bool":false}],"id":193},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Relapses are associated with which species of Plasmodium?","answers":[{"option":"Malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Vivax and ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Vivax and malariae","bool":false}],"id":194},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the below enlisted antiretroviral drugs is NOT a protease inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Cidofovir","bool":true},{"option":"Talepravir","bool":false},{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":false},{"option":"Lopinavir","bool":false},{"option":"Saquinavir","bool":false}],"id":195},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the following organs is not affected in mumps?","answers":[{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Testis","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":true}],"id":196},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is classified as a 'fluoroquinolone'?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfamethoxazole","bool":false}],"id":197},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the diagnostic investigation of choice for hydatid cyst disease?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasonography","bool":false},{"option":"MRI scan","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"MRCP","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true}],"id":198},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with a high-grade fever, irritability, and headache for the past 2 days. During inpatient evaluation, he develops a tonic-clonic fit that lasts for 1 minute. CSF examination reveals gram-negative diplococci with pleocytosis and high protein levels. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Neisseria meningitides","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus agalactiae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}],"id":199},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A histopathologist is evaluating a specimen under a microscope and describes it as 'spiral-shaped, with no gram staining'. Which of the following is the most likely specimen?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio parahaemolyticus","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true}],"id":200},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 5-year-old boy is brought to the emergency department with uncontrolled muscle spasms and lockjaw. A provisional diagnosis of tetanus is made and appropriate therapy is started. What is the antibiotic therapy for this infection?","answers":[{"option":"Metronidazole and penicillin both","bool":false},{"option":"Benzodiazepines","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Human tetanus immunoglobulin (HTIG)","bool":false}],"id":201},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 30-year-old male consults his doctor with the complaint of watery diarrhea for the past 3 days. He has to leave for a business trip and has heard of 'adsorbents' that help reduce acute watery diarrhea. Which of the following is an example of this class of antidiarrheal drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Diphenoxylate","bool":false},{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Kaolin","bool":true},{"option":"Docusate","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestyramine","bool":false}],"id":202},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of the antiprotozoal drug albendazole?","answers":[{"option":"Interfere with larval maturation","bool":false},{"option":"Increases gastric motility","bool":false},{"option":"Increases activity of cell membrane pumps","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits protozoal metabolic pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibit glucose utilization","bool":true}],"id":203},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the below-enlisted antibiotics inhibits protein synthesis via binding to the 50S subunit of bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false}],"id":204},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with fever and pain in his right cheek for the past 1 week. On clinical examination, unilateral facial swelling is observed. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mastoiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Sialolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false}],"id":205},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 30-year-old male, farmer by profession is being operated on for an 8 x 10 cm cyst visualized on an ultrasound abdomen. The patient presented with vague upper right-sided abdominal pain for the past 6 months. Surgical removal of the cyst reveals multiple daughter cysts. What is the causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":true},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false}],"id":206},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the most common type of tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Neonatal","bool":false},{"option":"Localized","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalic","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbar","bool":false},{"option":"Generalized","bool":true}],"id":207},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Which of the following organisms infect lymph nodes?","answers":[{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false}],"id":208},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the treatment of choice for Entamoeba histolytica infection?","answers":[{"option":"Paramomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Nitazoxanide","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Tinidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}],"id":209},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"A 24-year-old male commits murder via strangulation of his brother for money. What type of Qatl is this according to the Pakistan Penal Code?","answers":[{"option":"Qatl Shibh-i-Amd","bool":false},{"option":"Qatl-i-Khata","bool":false},{"option":"Qatl-Bis-Sabab","bool":false},{"option":"Qatl-i-Amd","bool":true},{"option":"Qatl-i-Jabr","bool":false}],"id":210},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Bansdola is an example of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Judicial hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Homicidal strangulation","bool":true},{"option":"Accidental strangulation","bool":false},{"option":"Lynching","bool":false},{"option":"Autoerotic hanging","bool":false}],"id":211},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the time period of formation of scab in abrasion?","answers":[{"option":"1 day","bool":true},{"option":"7-10 days","bool":false},{"option":"2-3 days","bool":false},{"option":"1 week","bool":false},{"option":"3-5 days","bool":false}],"id":212},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"What is the correct terminology for an injury involving the superficial layers of the skin?","answers":[{"option":"Graze","bool":false},{"option":"Laceration","bool":false},{"option":"Abrasion","bool":true},{"option":"Contusion","bool":false},{"option":"Incision","bool":false}],"id":213},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2018"],"question":"Why is a dying deposition considered better compared to a dying declaration?","answers":[{"option":"Less chance of fraud","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of witnesses","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of doctor","bool":false},{"option":"In written form","bool":false},{"option":"Recorded in presence of accused","bool":true}],"id":214},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"How many stool samples are required for the typhoid test?","answers":[{"option":"1","bool":false},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":true},{"option":"6","bool":false},{"option":"0","bool":false}],"id":215},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Infections caused by which of the following organisms cannot be treated with praziquantel?","answers":[{"option":"Diphyllobothriasis latum","bool":false},{"option":"Clonorchic sinensis","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":true},{"option":"Paragonimus westermani","bool":false}],"id":216},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is a common side effect of clofazimine?","answers":[{"option":"Red-green color blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Skin discoloration","bool":true},{"option":"Hair loss","bool":false},{"option":"Dizziness","bool":false},{"option":"Burning micturition","bool":false}],"id":217},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What anti-retroviral drug is a polypeptide that inhibits an HIV protein?","answers":[{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":false},{"option":"Nevirapine","bool":false},{"option":"Enfuvirtide","bool":true},{"option":"Raltegrase","bool":false},{"option":"Maraviroc","bool":false}],"id":218},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"The rapid urease test is a diagnostic test for which disease?","answers":[{"option":"Peptic ulcer disease","bool":true},{"option":"Cat scratch disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid disease","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory bowel disease","bool":false}],"id":219},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a mediator of fever in sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"IL-6","bool":false},{"option":"IL-17","bool":false},{"option":"IL-1","bool":true},{"option":"IL-11","bool":false},{"option":"IL-4","bool":false}],"id":220},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the migration of neutrophils to the site of injury from the capillaries called?","answers":[{"option":"Chemotaxis","bool":true},{"option":"Transmigration","bool":false},{"option":"Diapedesis","bool":false},{"option":"Extravasation","bool":false},{"option":"Diffusion","bool":false}],"id":221},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A person was walking barefoot in their yard and stubbed their toe on a rusted nail. Which of the following organisms is most likely to infect the injury?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pyogenes","bool":false},{"option":"Trichophyton tonsuran","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}],"id":222},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the etiology of pseudomembranous colitis?","answers":[{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":true},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Echinoccus granulosus","bool":false}],"id":223},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What organism causes leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Loa Loa","bool":false},{"option":"Leishmania donovani","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":true},{"option":"Schistosoma mansoni","bool":false}],"id":224},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is true about Plasmodium falciparum malaria?","answers":[{"option":"It resolves spontaneously","bool":false},{"option":"It is common in developed countries","bool":false},{"option":"It is asymptomatic mostly","bool":false},{"option":"It causes malignant tertian fever","bool":true},{"option":"It manifests after 7 days","bool":false}],"id":225},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A person was bitten by a mosquito and later developed malaria. Which of the following does the mosquito inject when it takes a blood meal?","answers":[{"option":"Schizont","bool":false},{"option":"Trophozoite","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoite","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoite","bool":true},{"option":"Hypnozoite","bool":false}],"id":226},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Prevention of fecal-oral transmission is unlikely to be achieved by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Drinking boiled water","bool":false},{"option":"Wearing masks","bool":true},{"option":"Proper waste disposal systems","bool":false},{"option":"Handwashing","bool":false},{"option":"Better sanitation","bool":false}],"id":227},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a danger sign in a neonate?","answers":[{"option":"Mid upper arm circumference >115 mm","bool":false},{"option":"Seizure","bool":true},{"option":"Weight for height/length >-2","bool":false},{"option":"Pallor","bool":false},{"option":"Coughing","bool":false}],"id":228},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What vaccines are given at birth according to the Expanded Program of Immunization (EPI) in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"BCG, OPV, and hepatitis B","bool":true},{"option":"BCG, IPV, and H. influenzae type B","bool":false},{"option":"MMR, IPV, and BCG","bool":false},{"option":"Measles, BCG, and OPV","bool":false},{"option":"IPV, BCG, and pneumococcal","bool":false}],"id":229},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the most likely complication of a bout of sexually transmitted disease (STD) caused by chlamydia?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease","bool":true},{"option":"Seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic cysts","bool":false},{"option":"Hypovolemia","bool":false},{"option":"Infertility","bool":false}],"id":230},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 19-year-old is brought to the clinic with complaints of epigastric abdominal pain and vomiting for the past 1 week. They were working barefoot in the fields preparing for the harvest. Physical examination reveals generalized pallor. Which of the following parasites would most likely be identified on stool examination?","answers":[{"option":"Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Ancyclostoma duodenale","bool":true},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false}],"id":231},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the treatment for tertiary syphilis?","answers":[{"option":"Single dose of intramuscular penicillin G","bool":false},{"option":"Azithromycin orally for 1 day","bool":false},{"option":"Benzathine penicillin G intramuscular thrice","bool":true},{"option":"Ampicillin 2 g intravenous every 6 hours","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous penicillin G for 14 days","bool":false}],"id":232},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is caused by rotavirus?","answers":[{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Spastic paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Gastroenteritis","bool":true},{"option":"Peripheral neuropathy","bool":false}],"id":233},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is true about the prevention of dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Awareness campaigns to increase better hygiene practices are effective","bool":false},{"option":"Improvement in sanitation limits mosquito reproduction","bool":true},{"option":"Masks are effective in limiting transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics provide effective prophylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"There is no vaccine available","bool":false}],"id":234},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not seen in Plasmodium falciparum malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Myalgia","bool":false},{"option":"Dyspnea","bool":true},{"option":"Rigors","bool":false}],"id":235},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A patient has worms in their eyes on examination. Which of the following organisms is most likely to cause such a presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Loa Loa","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis","bool":false},{"option":"Onchocerca volvulus","bool":false},{"option":"Wucheria bancrofti","bool":false}],"id":236},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A child has not been going to school because he has a vesicular rash over the face and trunk, along with a high-grade fever. 2 weeks ago the child went on a cruise where a boy had similar symptoms. What is the causative organism of this child's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes simplex virus 1","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue virus","bool":false},{"option":"Rubeola","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Varicella-zoster virus","bool":true}],"id":237},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 41-year-old man, with a history of HIV/AIDS, presents to the outpatient clinic with worsening dyspnea and cough for the last 5 days. The cough is non-productive and associated with a low-grade fever. A CD4+ count is ordered and is found to be 160 cells/mm3. Bronchoalveolar lavage, treated with methenamine silver staining, shows disc-shaped yeast cells. Which of the following organisms is most likely linked to this man's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory syncytial virus","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Burkholderia capacea","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}],"id":238},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 21-year-old woman presents to the clinic with a mild fever and increased urinary frequency. She complains of urinary hesitancy and also pain while urinating. She also reports pain in the pubic area after voiding. There is no history of chills, rigors, or nausea. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bladder dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":true}],"id":239},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A patient is admitted to the hospital for surgery. On the 8th day of admission, they develop fever, dyspnea, and productive cough. A chest X-ray shows consolidations in the right lower lobe. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hospital-acquired pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystocele","bool":false},{"option":"Transfusion-related acute lung injury","bool":false}],"id":240},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is not involved in the management of tetanus infections?","answers":[{"option":"Administering Tdap vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate debridement and cleaning of the wound","bool":false},{"option":"Administering intravenous benzylpenicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Administering oral aminoglycosides","bool":true},{"option":"Intramuscular injection of human tetanus immunoglobulin","bool":false}],"id":241},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the first line of treatment in a patient with tetanus?","answers":[{"option":"Tdap vaccine administered","bool":false},{"option":"Administer anti-pyretics","bool":false},{"option":"Human tetanus antitoxin administered","bool":true},{"option":"Aminoglycosides administered","bool":false},{"option":"Administer anti-inflammatory","bool":false}],"id":242},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is given in chloroquine-resistant plasmodium falciparum?","answers":[{"option":"Hydroxychloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Artesunate","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemesinin","bool":true},{"option":"Atovaquone","bool":false}],"id":243},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Dengue hemorrhagic fever is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombocytopenia and increased capillary permeability","bool":true},{"option":"Suppression of immune system","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased CD4+ cells","bool":false},{"option":"Rupturing cells releasing parasites into the bloodstream","bool":false},{"option":"Molecular mimicry","bool":false}],"id":244},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is the best method to diagnose mumps?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical examination","bool":true},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false}],"id":245},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is a likely punishment for those who fail to appear in court after a summons?","answers":[{"option":"Tazir","bool":false},{"option":"Daman","bool":false},{"option":"Diyat","bool":false},{"option":"Qisas","bool":false},{"option":"A fine","bool":true}],"id":246},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A man presents to the emergency department of the hospital and is referred to a medicolegal officer due to a suspicious stab wound on his abdomen. However, the clothes he wore had no incision. Which of the following is the best explanation for this man's case?","answers":[{"option":"Homicidal wounds","bool":false},{"option":"Fabricated wounds","bool":true},{"option":"Suicidal wounds","bool":false},{"option":"Defense wounds","bool":false},{"option":"Domestic abuse","bool":false}],"id":247},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following systems is most likely to be affected in kala-azar?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory system","bool":false},{"option":"Cariovascular system","bool":false},{"option":"Nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Reticuloendothelial system","bool":true},{"option":"Musculoskeletal system","bool":false}],"id":248},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Infection caused by which of the following organisms will lead to darkly colored urine?","answers":[{"option":"Ancyclostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":false},{"option":"Polio virus","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":false}],"id":249},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following counts as secondary prevention of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Biological control via natural predators","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine administered prophylactically","bool":true},{"option":"Administering malaria vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Indoor residual spraying","bool":false},{"option":"Insecticide-treated mosquito nets","bool":false}],"id":250},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which protozoa causes bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":true}],"id":251},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following organisms is visible under a Kinyon acid-fast stain?","answers":[{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":true},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":false}],"id":252},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the best initial test for HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Southwestern blot","bool":false},{"option":"Southern blot","bool":false},{"option":"Western blot","bool":false},{"option":"Northern blot","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":true}],"id":253},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A child has a vesicular rash over the face and trunk, along with a high-grade fever. 2 weeks ago the child went on a trip where another child had similar symptoms. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid fever","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":true}],"id":254},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 12-year-old boy presents to the clinic with a swollen jaw and pain upon chewing for 3 days. The swelling is bilateral and associated with mild fever. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":false},{"option":"Burkitt's lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis externa","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Infectious mononucleosis","bool":false}],"id":255},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What transmits the congo virus?","answers":[{"option":"Garden snails","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes agypti","bool":false},{"option":"Ixodes tic","bool":true},{"option":"Lice","bool":false},{"option":"Anopheles mosquito","bool":false}],"id":256},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A lucid interval is common in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal shock","bool":false},{"option":"Extradural hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Intracerebral hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false}],"id":257},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the predominant cell in acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true}],"id":258},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"The magic bullet phenomenon was seen in the assassination of which of the following personalities?","answers":[{"option":"Thomas Jefferson","bool":false},{"option":"Liaqat Ali Khan","bool":false},{"option":"Benazir Bhutto","bool":false},{"option":"John F. Kennedy","bool":true},{"option":"Abraham Lincoln","bool":false}],"id":259},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Aplastic anemia can be caused by an infectious agent. Which of the following is most likely to cause it?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii","bool":false},{"option":"Epstein-Barr virus","bool":true},{"option":"Trochophytan tonsurans","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false}],"id":260},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is farmer's lung?","answers":[{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity pneumonitis","bool":true},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis pneumonia","bool":false}],"id":261},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A 27-year-old male presents to the clinic with a complaint of fever for the past 2 days. Temperature is 102°F upon examination, blood pressure is 80/60 mmHg, respiratory rate is 24 breaths per minute, and heart rate is 64 beats per minute. He is admitted to the ward and a few hours later his fever is 104°F and then falls to 101°F. What is the most likely diagnosis in this man?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":false},{"option":"Blackwater fever","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid fever","bool":true},{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":false},{"option":"Hay fever","bool":false}],"id":262},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the appropriate treatment for typhoid fever in adults?","answers":[{"option":"Fluoroquinolones","bool":true},{"option":"Cephalosporins","bool":false},{"option":"Macrolides","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-lactamase inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false}],"id":263},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is untrue about chloramphenicol?","answers":[{"option":"Used in gram negative, positive, and Rickettsia infections","bool":false},{"option":"Binds to 50S ribosomal subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteriocidal","bool":true},{"option":"No longer used in the treatment of enteric fever","bool":false},{"option":"Broad-spectrum antibiotic","bool":false}],"id":264},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A greenstick fracture is commonly seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Infants","bool":true},{"option":"Pott's disease","bool":false},{"option":"Athletes","bool":false},{"option":"Elderly men","bool":false},{"option":"Postmenopausal women","bool":false}],"id":265},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the mechanism of resistance by Streptococcus pneumoniae towards beta-lactam antibiotics?","answers":[{"option":"Methylation of 23rRNA-bingind site","bool":false},{"option":"D-ala-D-ala mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin-binding protein alterations","bool":true},{"option":"Penicillinases","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylation","bool":false}],"id":266},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"An old man came with slowly progressive skin lesions on the chest and abdomen. He had a previous history of skin lesions that healed spontaneously. After doing investigations, he was a confirmed case of tuberculoid leprosy. What would be the treatment of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Ethambutol and linezolid","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide and chloramphenicol","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid and TMP-SMX","bool":false},{"option":"Dapsone and rifampin","bool":true},{"option":"Daptomycin and streptomycin","bool":false}],"id":267},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is seen in dapsone toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Neutropenia","bool":false},{"option":"Methemoglobinemia","bool":true},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Myopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Leucopenia","bool":false}],"id":268},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the management of tuberculosis in a patient with HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"HRZE for 6 months","bool":false},{"option":"HRZE for 2 months and HR for another 4 months","bool":true},{"option":"HR for 4 months and HRZE for 4 months","bool":false},{"option":"HRZE for 8 months","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine for 4 months with isoniazid","bool":false}],"id":269},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What is the drug of choice in neurocysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylcarbamazine","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true}],"id":270},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"What condition requires cautious dosing of primaquine?","answers":[{"option":"Pyruvate kinase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Glucocerebrosidase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersplenism","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen phosphorylase deficiency","bool":false}],"id":271},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"Which of the following is seen in fluoroquinolone toxicity?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage damage","bool":true},{"option":"Ototoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Disulfiram-like reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotoxicity","bool":false}],"id":272},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2019"],"question":"A patient is admitted to the intensive care unit due to sepsis. He is being mechanically ventilated. What should be the central venous pressure (CVP)?","answers":[{"option":"8-12 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"10-15 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"12-15 mm Hg","bool":true},{"option":"1-5 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 mm Hg","bool":false}],"id":273},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is not used for leprosy treatment anymore?","answers":[{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Thalidomide","bool":true},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false}],"id":274},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Ingestion of which of the following cause(s) human cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia solium eggs","bool":true},{"option":"Taenia saginata eggs and larvae","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata larvae","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata eggs","bool":false},{"option":"Pork containing cysticerci","bool":false}],"id":275},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following laboratory tests is useful for the management of patients infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis C virus (HCV) DNA","bool":false},{"option":"White blood cell count","bool":false},{"option":"CD4-positive T cell count","bool":true},{"option":"HIV antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"p24 antigen","bool":false}],"id":276},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Curschmann spirals are spiral-shaped mucus plugs that arise from subepithelial mucus glands in bronchi. These spirals are associated with many lung diseases. Which of the following diseases presents with these spirals?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Aspergillosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}],"id":277},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Mumps virus is an RNA virus that is transmitted through respiratory droplets and has an incubation period of 18-21 days. It presents with fever, malaise, and anorexia followed by unilateral or bilateral parotid swelling. How is mumps diagnosed?","answers":[{"option":"Complement fixation test","bool":false},{"option":"Hemagglutination inhibition test","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps skin test","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal fluid culture","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical examination","bool":true}],"id":278},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Atopic asthma is a type-1 hypersensitivity reaction that involves the lower respiratory tract. It occurs as a result of inhalation of antigen that causes the degranulation of sensitized mast cells present in the nasal or bronchiolar mucosa. This disease is mostly present in which age group?","answers":[{"option":"Any age","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood","bool":true},{"option":"Adulthood","bool":false},{"option":"Old age","bool":false},{"option":"Infancy","bool":false}],"id":279},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 17-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of high-grade, intermittent fever for the past 3 days. He also complains of associated rigor and chills and intense backache. Examination reveals a petechial rash over his shins. His complete blood count (CBC) reveals; hemoglobin 12.1 g/dL, total leukocyte count (TLC) 2.9 x 10^3/L, and platelets 39 x 10^3/L. What is the patient suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":false},{"option":"Acute malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Meningococcal meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Infective endocarditis","bool":false}],"id":280},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is used for the treatment of inoperable hydatid cysts?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Fluconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroid","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false}],"id":281},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 1-year-old girl is brought by her parents to the outpatient department (OPD) with complaints of fever and rashes. The doctor on-duty suspects measles. At what stage can measles spread to others?","answers":[{"option":"Patient remains infectious up to 2 weeks after the appearance of rashes","bool":false},{"option":"Three days before the appearance of rash upto 4 to 6 days after its onset","bool":true},{"option":"Seven days before the appearance of rash upto 5 days after its onset","bool":false},{"option":"The day of appearance of rash till 7 days after the onset","bool":false},{"option":"Ten days before the appearance of rash upto 7 days after its onset","bool":false}],"id":282},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the definitive host of the tiny tapeworm, Echinococcus granulosus?","answers":[{"option":"Cattle","bool":false},{"option":"Camel","bool":false},{"option":"Sheep","bool":false},{"option":"Human","bool":false},{"option":"Dogs","bool":true}],"id":283},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which drug inhibits the protein synthesis by reversibly binding to the 50S subunit of the bacterial ribosome and thereby restricting the formation of peptide bonds?","answers":[{"option":"Actinomycin-D","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporins","bool":false}],"id":284},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"What is the most commonly proposed mechanism for the cause of sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Drug-induced","bool":false},{"option":"Fungal infection","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Disordered immune regulation","bool":true}],"id":285},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following side effects is not associated with fluoroquinolones?","answers":[{"option":"Hallucinations","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Deafness","bool":true},{"option":"Damage to growing cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Phototoxicity","bool":false}],"id":286},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"An afebrile patient comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of passing large number of stools frequently. On microscopic examination of the stool, no red blood cells and white blood cells are found. Which of the following conditions best relate to the patient's complaint?","answers":[{"option":"Watery diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Indigestion","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Infectious","bool":false}],"id":287},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A urea breath test is performed on a patient of which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Enterocolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Enteric fever","bool":false},{"option":"Acid peptic disease","bool":true},{"option":"Cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Liver abscess","bool":false}],"id":288},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a typical clinical finding in the case of cryptosporidiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Watery diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for long duration","bool":false},{"option":"Non bloody diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for long duration","bool":false},{"option":"Watery diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for short duration","bool":true},{"option":"Self limiting diarrhea in immunocompromised patients","bool":false},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea in immunocompetent patients for short duration","bool":false}],"id":289},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"When taking the history of diarrhea in children, what is the most important combination of signs or symptoms that is needed to be asked?","answers":[{"option":"Frequency and smell","bool":false},{"option":"Color and consistency","bool":false},{"option":"Frequency and consistency","bool":false},{"option":"Duration and smell","bool":false},{"option":"Color and duration","bool":true}],"id":290},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 20-year-old college student, who has returned from his trip to India, now presents with fever and malaise. His peripheral blood smear confirms the presence of malaria species. His physician prescribes him chloroquine and asks him to take rest at home. What is the problem with this physician's choice of treatment of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"He should also have prescribed a drug to treat yellow fever because these diseases are often transmitted together","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine is not the drug of choice, he should have prescribed albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine is unnecessary because malaria infection is short lived and benign","bool":false},{"option":"He should have prescribed primaquine in addition to chloroquine","bool":true},{"option":"There is nothing wrong with this prescription","bool":false}],"id":291},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 40-year-old male is bitten by a sandfly and has presented to the outpatient department with an ulcerated red papule. The doctor suspects infection with Leishmania tropica. Which of the following is found in the skin lesion smear for the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Amastigotes","bool":true},{"option":"Trophozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Promastigotes","bool":false}],"id":292},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most important toxicity of amphotericin B?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotoxicity","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow depression","bool":false},{"option":"Neurotoxicity","bool":false}],"id":293},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Pap smear of a 30-year-old female, who is admitted to the hospital, shows intraepithelial neoplasia. To confirm the type of human papillomavirus (HPV), a polymerase chain reaction (PCR) is carried out, which shows the presence of HPV-16 and HPV-18 genotypes of human papillomavirus. Which one of the following is correct about human papillomavirus?","answers":[{"option":"HPV-16 and HPV-18 cause genital warts","bool":false},{"option":"Skin warts are most common","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical diagnosis is not helpful","bool":false},{"option":"Vertical transmission is not found","bool":false},{"option":"Koilocytes are the hallmark of infection","bool":true}],"id":294},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 35-year-old male comes to the outpatient department (OPD) with complaints of high-grade fever associated with chills, nausea, vomiting. The doctor diagnoses him with the case of malaria caused by Plasmodium falciparum. Which of the following is the life-threatening complication of this type of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Bone marrow failure","bool":false},{"option":"Acute hepatic failure","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":true},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly","bool":false}],"id":295},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 27-year-old boy is started with a human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) drug regimen after the diagnosis of HIV infection. Which of the following drugs blocks the cleavage of HIV polyproteins?","answers":[{"option":"Maraviroc","bool":false},{"option":"Enfuvirtide","bool":false},{"option":"Delavirdine","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Darunavir","bool":true}],"id":296},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A young male experiences skin discoloration after the start of drug therapy for leprosy. His skin color ranges from red-brown to black. Which of the following drugs causes this side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Rifabutin","bool":false},{"option":"Acedapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfadoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":true},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false}],"id":297},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Leprosy (also known as Hansen's disease) can be treated efficiently with dapsone and rifampin along with clofazimine in multibacillary cases. Which of the following enzymes is inhibited by one of the leprosy drugs mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Dihydropteroate synthetase enzyme","bool":true},{"option":"Acetyltransferase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Dihydrofolate reductase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"DNA-gyrase enzyme","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase IV enzyme","bool":false}],"id":298},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 46-year-old female suffers an injury on her foot with a rusty nail while walking barefoot on her lawn. She rushes to the emergency department and seeks medical help. The doctor cleans her wound with normal saline and dresses her wound. Which of the following is most likely to cause an infection in her case?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium sordellii","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false}],"id":299},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A young man presents to the emergency department with a complaint of non-bloody diarrhea for the past 3 days. Stool culture is ordered. The culture reveals gram-negative rods with lactose fermenting colonies. Which of the following organisms is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococci","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false}],"id":300},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A young male, living in a non-malarious area, plans to visit an area where chloroquine-resistant Plasmodium falciparum is common. He is known to be intolerant to mefloquine and his glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) status is not known. Which of the following drugs will be prescribed to him for prophylaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Amoquine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":true},{"option":"Amodiaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false}],"id":301},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is a drug of choice for cerebral cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prednisolone","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocortisone","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false}],"id":302},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of peripheral nerve thickening?","answers":[{"option":"Alcoholism","bool":false},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV infection","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Marie-Tooth Disease","bool":false},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":true}],"id":303},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 45-year-old male comes to his doctor with the chief complaints of fever, night sweats, and increased episodes of diarrhea during the past month. He has lost 30 pounds over the past 4 months. On physical exam, he has oral thrush and cervical lymphadenopathy. The patient has a contact history as well. The clinician has a strong suspicion of human immune deficiency virus (HIV) infection. Which of the following is the confirmatory test for HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Western blot test","bool":true},{"option":"Viral genome amplification (PCP)","bool":false},{"option":"Virus culture","bool":false},{"option":"Antigen/antibody detection (ELISA)","bool":false},{"option":"Point of care test (POT)","bool":false}],"id":304},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 38-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of generalized weakness and chronic diarrhea. He has had excessive weight loss over the past few months. He gives a history of drug abuse. Suspecting HIV, which screening test should be advised?","answers":[{"option":"Western blot","bool":false},{"option":"ELISA","bool":true},{"option":"HIV viral load test","bool":false},{"option":"Absolute CD4⁺ lymphocyte count","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false}],"id":305},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not used for the management of Clostridium difficile-associated diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Stop the offending antibiotic","bool":false},{"option":"Patient should be isolated","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous vancomycin","bool":true}],"id":306},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"The presumptive diagnosis of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection is sometimes made with the help of antibodies found in the patient's serum using enzyme-linked immunoassay (ELISA). Which test is confirmatory for HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"Antigen/antibody detection (ELISA)","bool":false},{"option":"Point of care testing (POCT)","bool":false},{"option":"Western blot test","bool":true},{"option":"Viral genome amplification (PCR)","bool":false},{"option":"Virus culture","bool":false}],"id":307},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following can not be prevented by the protective measures taken against the mosquitoes?","answers":[{"option":"Congo Crimean hemorrhagic fever","bool":true},{"option":"Chikungunya fever","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria fever","bool":false}],"id":308},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is correct for Enterobius vermicularis?","answers":[{"option":"It is transmitted by mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"It can cause elephantiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Its trophozoites can be recovered from diarrheal stools","bool":false},{"option":"Perianal pruritus is its most prominent symptom","bool":true},{"option":"Its infection occurs in animals","bool":false}],"id":309},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is/are contraindicated in dengue?","answers":[{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"NSAID and aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Antimalarial","bool":false},{"option":"Antiemetics","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false}],"id":310},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which can help in the diagnosis of factitious fever?","answers":[{"option":"Increased ESR and CRP","bool":false},{"option":"Normal temperature during supervised measurement","bool":true},{"option":"A patient who looks unwell","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of diurnal variation","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of swelling during defervescence","bool":false}],"id":311},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"During the fight, Faisal amputates Shahid's finger with a sharp knife. Which of the following criminal act has Faisal caused?","answers":[{"option":"Jaifah","bool":false},{"option":"Itlaf-i-salahiyyat-i-udw","bool":false},{"option":"Itlaf-i-udw","bool":true},{"option":"Jurh","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah","bool":false}],"id":312},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 27-year-old pregnant lady arrives at the emergency with extreme labor pain and is rushed to the labor room for the delivery. Her history suggests that she previously had a herpes simplex virus 2 infection.  Which of the following is correct for neonatal herpes?","answers":[{"option":"Neonatal infection is more likely to occur when mother is suffering from recurrent infection","bool":false},{"option":"Amount of virus produced during primary infection is less than produced in a secondary infection","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal herpes chiefly originates from contact with vesicular lesions within the birth canal","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal delivery has lesser chances of delivering infection to neonate as compared with caesarean section","bool":false},{"option":"Mother would pass IgM antibodies which can protect neonate from disseminated infection","bool":false}],"id":313},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of niclosamide?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of phosphorylation of ADP in some species of helminths","bool":true},{"option":"Lysis of helminthic proteins through decrease in intracellular pH","bool":false},{"option":"Blocking acetylcholine transmission at the myoneural junction and paralysis of helminths","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of microtubule synthesis in helminths and irreversible impairment of glucose uptake","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing cell membrane permeability for calcium, resulting in paralysis, dislodgement and death of helminths","bool":false}],"id":314},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 30-year-old man presents to the medical outpatient department with a complaint of pain during urination. He also complains of purulent urethral discharge and gives a history of sexual contact 7 days ago. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydial urethritis","bool":false},{"option":"Primary syphilis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas infection","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":true}],"id":315},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 2-year-old boy is brought by his parents to the emergency room with papulovesicular rash present on the trunk, head, and extremities. His parents also mention the history of fever and malaise for the past 4 days. His mother further adds that the same rash has also presented on their neighbor's child.  What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Measles virus","bool":false},{"option":"Varicella - zoster virus","bool":true},{"option":"Mumps virus","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex II","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex I","bool":false}],"id":316},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A middle-aged man presents to the outpatient department with complaints of headache, vomiting, and seizures after he ate undercooked pork. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain is carried out, which reveals multiple lesions bilaterally. The doctor diagnosed him with cysticercosis of the brain. Which of the following parasites is responsible for cysticercosis?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":true},{"option":"Hymenolepis nana","bool":false}],"id":317},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Ali and Ahmed get into a fight outside the school. Ali punches Ahmed hard enough to cause a fracture of the mandible along with the anterior dislocation. Which type of injury has Ali caused?","answers":[{"option":"Shajjah-i-mudihah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-munaqqilah","bool":true},{"option":"Shajjah-i-ammah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-khafifah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah-i-damighah","bool":false}],"id":318},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 14-year-old girl presents to the clinic with complaints of fever, headache, and neck rigidity. Cerebrospinal fluid examination reveals increased polymorphonuclear cells and Gram staining reveals the presence of gram-negative diplococci. Which of the following is the most likely causative micro-organism?","answers":[{"option":"Branhamella species","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false}],"id":319},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 36-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, weakness , weight loss and massive splenomegaly. He is suspected to be infected by Leishmania donovani, which is the cause of kala azar (visceral leishmaniasis). Which system of the body is affected by this infection?","answers":[{"option":"Reticuloendothelial system","bool":true},{"option":"Immune system","bool":false},{"option":"Gastrointestinal system","bool":false},{"option":"Endocrine system","bool":false},{"option":"Nervous system","bool":false}],"id":320},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In dengue infection, the hemorrhagic shock syndrome occurs due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukin-1 acting on hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Increased vascular permeability and thrombocytopenia due to complement activity","bool":true},{"option":"High grade fever","bool":false},{"option":"Depletion of water and electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Ulceration of gastrointestinal tract","bool":false}],"id":321},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In which of the following helminthic infestation albendazole is the drug of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Hydatid disease","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ascariasis","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Ankylostomiasis","bool":false}],"id":322},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with profuse diarrhea. He has now developed kidney failure, thrombocytopenia, and hemolytic anemia. His blood smear reveals fragmented red blood cells called\r\nschistocytes. What is the most likely causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Enterotoxigenic E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enteroaggregative E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enteropathogenic E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"Enteroinvasive E. coli","bool":false}],"id":323},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 10-year-old boy is brought to the emergency room with complaints of fever and abdominal cramps, followed by diarrhea which was initially watery but later contained blood and mucus. Colorless colonies are seen on MacConkey's agar. Which of the following characteristics is correct regarding the organism involved?","answers":[{"option":"O antigen","bool":true},{"option":"Lactose-fermenters","bool":false},{"option":"Produce H2S","bool":false},{"option":"Motile","bool":false},{"option":"High ID50","bool":false}],"id":324},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 12-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department with abdominal pain. He is barefooted, pale, and malnourished, with a protruded abdomen. Physical examination reveals anemia. Which of the following parasites will be identified from stool examination?","answers":[{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoides","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":true},{"option":"Balantidium coli","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false}],"id":325},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is not sexually transmitted?","answers":[{"option":"Molluscum contagiosum","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Anogenital warts","bool":false},{"option":"Genital candidiasis","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false}],"id":326},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common extra-salivary manifestation of mumps after puberty?","answers":[{"option":"Mastitis","bool":false},{"option":"Oophoritis","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymo-orchitis","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false}],"id":327},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which history is not significant to ask from a patient who presents with a suspected case of sexually transmitted infection?","answers":[{"option":"Do you have a regular sexual partner at present?","bool":false},{"option":"Do/did you use condom?","bool":false},{"option":"When did you last have sex?","bool":false},{"option":"In your life, have your sexual partners been male, female or both?","bool":false},{"option":"Do you masturbate on regular basis?","bool":true}],"id":328},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Due to the risk of which of the following is it mandatory for the people traveling to Africa to get vaccinated?","answers":[{"option":"Congo fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Lassa fever","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":true}],"id":329},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 20-year-old female presents with a history of fever for five days. She also complains of abdominal pain and constipation. On examination, the temperature is 101 F, the pulse is 68 beats per minute and the rest is unremarkable. The doctor suspects enteric fever. Which of the following is true regarding the investigation?","answers":[{"option":"The sensitivity of typhidot is nearly 100%","bool":false},{"option":"Urine culture is positive in first week","bool":false},{"option":"Stool culture is positive in the first week","bool":false},{"option":"Widal test is the most sensitive","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture is the most useful diagnostic test at this stage","bool":true}],"id":330},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 20-year-old male is given ceftriaxone for the treatment of gonorrhea. Which of the following antibiotic groups does this antibiotic belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Cell membrane inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"DNA synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Cell-wall synthesis inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"Folic acid synthesis inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Protein synthesis inhibitor","bool":false}],"id":331},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 25-year-old woman from the Lyari district comes to the emergency department with complaints of severe abdominal pain, nausea, anorexia, flatulence, and abdominal cramps with diarrhea. She tells that she has had the same complaints two weeks before as well. Complete blood count shows marked leukocytosis while the stool examination shows pear-shaped trophozoites. What would the most probable diagnosis be?","answers":[{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial infection","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":true},{"option":"Trichomonas","bool":false}],"id":332},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 30-year-old male has a road accident, he comes to the emergency department with severe pain and presented with several bruises on different body parts. The physician immediately starts anti-inflammatory agents as a treatment strategy. Which of the following is a hallmark of acute inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Granuloma formation","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false}],"id":333},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A child is brought to the clinic for medical consultation with complaints of painful swelling of the parotid gland, fever and difficulty in swallowing. What would be the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Burkitt lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Infectious mononucleosis","bool":false},{"option":"Adenoviral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Influenza","bool":false}],"id":334},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"The late stage of the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection is acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). The decline in the number of which of the following cells manifests this stage?","answers":[{"option":"CD8+ T cells","bool":false},{"option":"CD4+ T cells","bool":true},{"option":"CD40 cells","bool":false},{"option":"CD28 cells","bool":false},{"option":"MHC class I cells","bool":false}],"id":335},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following antimalarial drugs is used for the treatment of chloroquine-resistant falciparum malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Proguanil","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemisinin","bool":true},{"option":"Sulfadoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false}],"id":336},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 35-year-old male consults to physician after being bitten by a stranded dog within 24 hours. What post-exposure prophylaxis regime will the doctor offer him after local wound care or cleaning?","answers":[{"option":"10 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) plus 5 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV)","bool":false},{"option":"20 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) alone","bool":false},{"option":"5 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV); intramuscular (I/M)","bool":false},{"option":"20 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) plus 3 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV)","bool":false},{"option":"20 IU/kg human rabies immunoglobulin (HRIG) plus 5 doses of 1 ml human diploid cell vaccine (HDCV)","bool":true}],"id":337},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with a history of prolonged cough, fever and chest infection. He is diagnosed with a case of tuberculosis after getting confirmation from the report of biopsy. Which one of the following would have been the identifying feature of tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Infiltration of eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Congested blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Granuloma formation","bool":true},{"option":"Collection of serous fluid","bool":false}],"id":338},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with fever, abdominal cramps, and a history of passing only a small amount of loose stools. Lab findings show mucous, red blood cells, and white blood cells in the stool sample. Which of the following best describes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Food poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":true},{"option":"Indigestion","bool":false},{"option":"Watery diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Bloody diarrhea","bool":false}],"id":339},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A very effective vaccine for which of the following is available to prevent diarrhea in children?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":true}],"id":340},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A young male presents with painless profuse diarrhea. He is passing a large volume of stool flecked with mucus. He presents to the emergency response department dehydrated and in a state of shock. Which of the following is an appropriate statement if cholera is suspected?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperchlorhydria facilitates the passage of cholera bacilli into the small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"It releases GABA which is responsible for its secretory effect","bool":false},{"option":"Cholera toxin is an enterotoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Cholera toxin releases 5-hydroxytryptamine from enterochromaffin cells in the gut","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea occurs because of vibrio cholera invasive action","bool":false}],"id":341},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 34-year-old intravenous drug abuser comes with bloody diarrhea for 3 months. Which of the following is the most common protozoan causing bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Microsporidium","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":true},{"option":"Isospora belli","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false}],"id":342},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"An antiviral drug ritonavir acts by inhibiting which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Peptidyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-lactamase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":false},{"option":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) protease","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrolase","bool":false}],"id":343},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In which of the following conditions can the anti-inflammatory effect of chloroquine be used?","answers":[{"option":"Cellulitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatic fever","bool":false},{"option":"Myocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true}],"id":344},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Chronic granulomatous inflammation is microscopically characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Fibrous tissue formation","bool":false},{"option":"New blood vessels formation (angiogenesis)","bool":false},{"option":"Circumscribed collection of epithelioid and multinucleated giant cells","bool":true},{"option":"Sheets of epithelioid cells","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse infiltration by lymphocytes","bool":false}],"id":345},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Complications of measles can be very severe in certain cases. Which of the following is not considered a complication occurring several years after the episode of measles?","answers":[{"option":"Panencephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Orchitis","bool":true},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false}],"id":346},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the more frequent cause of bloody diarrhea in children?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":true},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Rota virus","bool":false}],"id":347},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the characteristic of dengue?","answers":[{"option":"Fever without rash","bool":false},{"option":"Transient rash","bool":false},{"option":"Rash without fever","bool":false},{"option":"Neither rash nor fever","bool":false},{"option":"Fever with rash","bool":true}],"id":348},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Elephantiasis is caused by blockage of the lymphatic system. Which of the following is the most common cause of elephantiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Wuchereria bancrofti","bool":true},{"option":"Trichinella spiralis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false}],"id":349},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is endotoxin, an integral part of?","answers":[{"option":"Fungal cell wall","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative rods and cocci","bool":true},{"option":"Gram positive rods","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive cocci","bool":false},{"option":"Normal cells of body","bool":false}],"id":350},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Fever, a biological effect of endotoxin, occurs due to the release of which of the following endogenous pyrogens?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukin-4","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-5","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-2","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-12","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":true}],"id":351},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In a male diagnosed with a sexually transmitted infection, microscopic examination of fluid from the lesions reveals spiral microorganisms that can not be stained by Gram's staining procedure. What would the microorganism most likely be?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia species","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Borrelia species","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":true},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false}],"id":352},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In a stool sample of a 10-year-old Muslim child admitted for abdominal pain, flat ribbon-like segments with scolices are seen. What would the most probable diagnosis be?","answers":[{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":true},{"option":"Trichuris trichiura","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false}],"id":353},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Leprosy is a chronic granulomatous disease causing multiple deformities of extremities. Which of the following statements is correct regarding its incubation period?","answers":[{"option":"The incubation period averages several hours","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages few months","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages few weeks","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages few days","bool":false},{"option":"The incubation period averages several years","bool":true}],"id":354},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Leprosy is caused by Mycobacterium leprae, characterized by loss of sensation in the periphery. Which of the following is true regarding the duration of treatment of tuberculoid leprosy?","answers":[{"option":"Treatment is given for one year","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment is given for six months","bool":true},{"option":"Treatment is given for two years","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment is given for one month","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment is given for three months","bool":false}],"id":355},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Measles is primarily a childhood disease characterized by fever, runny nose, cough, and maculopapular rash. What is its diagnosis usually done by?","answers":[{"option":"Rise in antibody titer","bool":false},{"option":"History and physical examination","bool":true},{"option":"Virus cell culture","bool":false},{"option":"RNA hybridization test","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction","bool":false}],"id":356},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following results in the primary immune defect of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased cellular immunity","bool":false},{"option":"Low synthesis of immunoglobulin","bool":false},{"option":"Reduction of number and effectiveness of CD4+ T cells due to killing induced by human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)","bool":true},{"option":"Killing of CD4+ T cells due to antibody-dependent cytotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Inactivation of phagocytic cells","bool":false}],"id":357},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is most accurate regarding human papillomavirus (HPV)?","answers":[{"option":"Human papillomavirus causes genital warts and cervical cancer","bool":true},{"option":"The capsid protein P2 of human papillomavirus activates the C-scars oncogene in human cells","bool":false},{"option":"Blood and blood products are important modes of transmission","bool":false},{"option":"Human papillomavirus causes the infection of upper respiratory tract and lower respiratory tract mainly","bool":false},{"option":"Human papillomavirus is an enveloped virus with RNA genome","bool":false}],"id":358},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"On the basis of which of the following can Shigella be differentiated from Salmonella?","answers":[{"option":"Having very low infectious dose (ID50)","bool":true},{"option":"Being gram negative","bool":false},{"option":"Growth on MacConkey's medium","bool":false},{"option":"Being non-lactose fermenters","bool":false},{"option":"Being able to produce hydrogen sulphide (H2S)","bool":false}],"id":359},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In which of the following does the sporogony take place?","answers":[{"option":"Environment","bool":false},{"option":"Mosquito gut","bool":true},{"option":"Salivary glands of mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cells","bool":false},{"option":"Human blood","bool":false}],"id":360},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In the pathogenesis of which of the following diseases is the superantigen production by Staphylococcus aureus involved?","answers":[{"option":"Impetigo","bool":false},{"option":"Scalded skin syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Food poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false}],"id":361},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"If a multi-bacillary leprosy patient, treated with standard fixed-duration multi-drug therapy, starts having relapses, what among the following regimen should be started?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin + dapsone + clofazimine","bool":true},{"option":"Ofloxacin  + minocycline + clarithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine + ofloxacin + minocycline","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin + dapsone + ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine + ofloxacin + clarithromycin","bool":false}],"id":362},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"What will be the best specimen to find Entamoeba histolytica cysts?","answers":[{"option":"Urine of the diarrheal patient","bool":false},{"option":"Blood of asymptomatic carrier","bool":false},{"option":"Blood of the diarrheal patient","bool":false},{"option":"Stool of the diarrheal patient","bool":false},{"option":"Stool of asymptomatic carrier","bool":true}],"id":363},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In which stage or phase of human acquired immunodeficiency (HIV) virus infection is the term 'acquired immunodeficiency syndrome' (AIDS) used to denote the disease?","answers":[{"option":"Infective period of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false},{"option":"Initial phase of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false},{"option":"Incubation period of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false},{"option":"Last stage of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":true},{"option":"Convalescent phase of human acquired immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection","bool":false}],"id":364},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding Plasmodium falciparum?","answers":[{"option":"Anemia is not significant","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly is not a feature","bool":false},{"option":"Relapses occur every 3 months","bool":false},{"option":"It causes malignant tertian infection","bool":true},{"option":"Characteristically, paroxysm occurs every 72 hours","bool":false}],"id":365},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Viral hemorrhagic fever is caused by a group of viruses that mostly attack the vascular system. Which of the following virus families does the dengue virus belong to?","answers":[{"option":"Bunyaviridae","bool":false},{"option":"Arenaviridae","bool":false},{"option":"Ebola","bool":false},{"option":"Flaviviridae","bool":true},{"option":"Floviviridae","bool":false}],"id":366},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Complete blood count (CBC) examination of the blood taken from a patient with a history of fever reveals distorted red blood cells (RBCs) double of its size with Schüffner's dots. Which of the following protozoa is responsible for that picture?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false}],"id":367},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Dengue is also known as breakbone fever. Which of the following statements is true regarding the causative organism of this disease?","answers":[{"option":"It is a protozoan parasite","bool":false},{"option":"It is a DNA enveloped virus","bool":false},{"option":"It is a RNA non-enveloped virus","bool":false},{"option":"It is a RNA enveloped virus","bool":true},{"option":"It is a DNA non-enveloped virus","bool":false}],"id":368},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"In the life cycle of parasites, what is the 'definitive host' defined as?","answers":[{"option":"A host who is an obligatory part of life cycle","bool":false},{"option":"A host in which asexual reproduction occurs","bool":false},{"option":"A host in which life cycle can end","bool":false},{"option":"A host in which sexual reproduction occurs","bool":true},{"option":"A host that acts as a vector in transporting the parasite from infected host","bool":false}],"id":369},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Why is the infection with Plasmodium falciparum called 'malignant malaria'?","answers":[{"option":"Causes malignancies","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular paroxysms","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple infection in red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Adherence and blockage of capillaries of internal organs","bool":true},{"option":"Absence of relapses","bool":false}],"id":370},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of perianal pruritus?","answers":[{"option":"Pinworm infection","bool":true},{"option":"Loiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Whipworm infection","bool":false},{"option":"Filariasis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichinosis","bool":false}],"id":371},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2020"],"question":"A 22-year-old student comes with a positive test for the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). He is taking intravenous drugs for the past year. His physical examination is unremarkable. His laboratory tests and investigations are all fine, and the CD4+ lymphocyte count is within the normal range at 750. What would the best course of action be to start antiretroviral therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Once he has stopped using drugs","bool":false},{"option":"When his CD4+ cell count is below 300","bool":false},{"option":"When he starts to show initial signs of infection","bool":false},{"option":"When his human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) viral load is approaching 1 million","bool":false},{"option":"Immediately","bool":true}],"id":372},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is a preferred prophylactic regimen of malaria in pregnant women?","answers":[{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":true}],"id":373},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors may lead to gastrointestinal toxicity, such as pancreatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Didanosine","bool":true},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":false},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false}],"id":374},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitors causes antagonism with zidovudine?","answers":[{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":true},{"option":"Didanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":false}],"id":375},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A medical man appeared in the court to record his statement. After recording, he feels that the court might misinterpret his observations, which may likely lead to a miscarriage of justice. What can he do in this scenario to ensure that justice is served right?","answers":[{"option":"Record his protest","bool":false},{"option":"Volunteer a statement","bool":true},{"option":"Withdraw his statement","bool":false},{"option":"Modify his statement","bool":false},{"option":"Make an appeal","bool":false}],"id":376},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Conduct money is given in a case involving which offense?","answers":[{"option":"Murder","bool":false},{"option":"Shoplifting","bool":false},{"option":"Homicide","bool":false},{"option":"Rape","bool":false},{"option":"Divorce","bool":true}],"id":377},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Koplik's spots are characteristic enanthem of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Macules","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}],"id":378},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following laboratory tests can help make a presumptive diagnosis of varicella-zoster virus infection?","answers":[{"option":"Gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Tzanck smear","bool":true},{"option":"Serologic tests","bool":false},{"option":"Giemsa stain","bool":false}],"id":379},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"In the court of law, during the recording of evidence, leading questions are only allowed during cross-examination. Which of the following is the only other condition where the prosecution can ask leading questions?","answers":[{"option":"Re-examination","bool":false},{"option":"Volunteering a statement","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical examiners testimony","bool":false},{"option":"Privileged communication","bool":false},{"option":"Witness is declared hostile","bool":true}],"id":380},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 55-year-old male presents with fever, weight loss, and cough with hemoptysis for the past 2 weeks. His sputum is acid-fast bacillus (AFB) smear-positive. What is the likely diagnosis of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}],"id":381},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Maculopapular rash and posterior auricular lymphadenopathy are the characteristic signs of which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken Pox","bool":false},{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":true}],"id":382},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following anti-leprotic drugs can cause pink to brownish-black discoloration of the skin with an itchy-dry texture?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Dapsone","bool":false},{"option":"Moxifloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Clofazimine","bool":true}],"id":383},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following clinical signs indicates sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"Heart rate > 85 breaths per minute","bool":false},{"option":"Partial pressure of oxygen < 80 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia < 140 mg/dl","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory rate < 16 breaths per minute","bool":false},{"option":"White blood cell count > 12,000 mm³ or <4000 mm³","bool":true}],"id":384},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Crescent-shaped gametocytes are found in infection by which of the following plasmodium species?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}],"id":385},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 10-year-old-child is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of headache, neck stiffness, and fever. Bacterial culture was done, and Neisseria meningitidis were isolated. What is the probable diagnosis of this case?","answers":[{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":true},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false}],"id":386},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 19-year-old-girl presents to the outpatient department with complaints of severe watery diarrhea. Upon history taking, she told about consuming shellfish at a party the previous night. Her bacterial cultures show colonies of a comma-shaped bacterium. What is the causative organism of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella toxin","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false}],"id":387},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following factors indicates a poor prognosis of Crimean-Congo Hemorrhagic Virus?","answers":[{"option":"Liver necrosis and cerebral haemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatomegaly and splenomegaly","bool":false},{"option":"Fever and gastrointestinal disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Myalgia and vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Encephalopathy and respiratory distress","bool":false}],"id":388},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A girl got injured with a rusty nail by walking around barefoot. What organism is she at the risk of being affected with?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium septicum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false}],"id":389},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is true about dengue fever?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue virus belongs to the togavirus family","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue is transmitted by the Anopheles mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"The vaccine contains inactivated dengue virus","bool":false},{"option":"Humans are the reservoirs of dengue virus","bool":true},{"option":"Hematemesis is indicative of dengue fever","bool":false}],"id":390},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which form of plasmodium is inoculated by the Anopheles mosquito into humans?","answers":[{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Metacryptozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Gametozoites","bool":false}],"id":391},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is an example of criminal negligence?","answers":[{"option":"Not counting the gauzes used in operation","bool":false},{"option":"Not giving proper post-operative care","bool":false},{"option":"Surgically removing the fine eye instead of the diseased","bool":true},{"option":"Not attending to a labor patient","bool":false},{"option":"Giving injection on the wrong side or the wrong route","bool":false}],"id":392},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A student is in charge of the urogenital system and needs to decide who should be screened for gonorrhea. Out of the following options, which of the following groups of people does not need to be screened?","answers":[{"option":"Transgenders","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous drug abusers","bool":false},{"option":"Sex workers","bool":false},{"option":"Doctors treating gonorrhea patients","bool":true},{"option":"Clients of sex workers","bool":false}],"id":393},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following indicates sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with documented infection","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with lactic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with blood pressure < 90 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic inflammatory response syndrome with severe hypotension","bool":false}],"id":394},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is administered to a pregnant woman diagnosed with Chlamydial urethritis?","answers":[{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin V","bool":false}],"id":395},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following species of plasmodium causes malignant tertian malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium relictum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false}],"id":396},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"There is a patient with a clear indication of sepsis. To treat the resultant hypotension, intravenous fluids are administered, but they do not improve the condition significantly. What is the next step of treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Identification and removal of source of infection","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressors such as norepinephrine","bool":true},{"option":"Surgical debridement","bool":false},{"option":"Inoculation of antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of broad-spectrum antibiotics","bool":false}],"id":397},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following drugs directly inhibits human-immunodeficiency virus (HIV) reverse transcriptase without phosphorylation?","answers":[{"option":"Lamivudine","bool":false},{"option":"Nevirapene","bool":true},{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false}],"id":398},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the term used for diarrhea that lasts for at least 14 days and has no blood?","answers":[{"option":"Amebic dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentery","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Acute diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent diarrhea","bool":true}],"id":399},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 25-year-old man presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of watery diarrhea for the past few days. He also tells that he has recently traveled to Hunza. Which of the following pathogens is responsible for his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Enteropathogenic  E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxigenic E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Enteroinvasive E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic E. coli","bool":false}],"id":400},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is a protease inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Abacavir","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Efavirenz","bool":false},{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":true}],"id":401},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Tinidazole is better than metronidazole due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"It surpasses first pass effect","bool":false},{"option":"It is not active against anerobic bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"It has longer half-life","bool":true},{"option":"It is used in the pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"It has better absorption","bool":false}],"id":402},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Other than its anthelmintic activity, which of the following does tinidazole have activity against?","answers":[{"option":"Aerobic bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Obligate aerobe","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative cocci","bool":false},{"option":"Anaerobic bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"Gram positive cocci","bool":false}],"id":403},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A man presents to the outpatient department with a bite wound on his arm. He has cats and rats in her house. On examination, the bite marks look more likely of a rat. Which of the following animals will not transmit rabies?","answers":[{"option":"Mongooses","bool":false},{"option":"Donkey","bool":true},{"option":"Rat","bool":false},{"option":"Cat","bool":false},{"option":"Bat","bool":false}],"id":404},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the term used for a letter or a document issued by a court for the person under penalty to attend the court?","answers":[{"option":"Subpoena","bool":true},{"option":"Inquiry","bool":false},{"option":"Proof","bool":false},{"option":"Perjury","bool":false},{"option":"Evidence","bool":false}],"id":405},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which type of evidence establishes a fact or at least presumption of the fact on examination?","answers":[{"option":"Hearsay evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Documentary evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Direct evidence","bool":false},{"option":"Prima facie","bool":true}],"id":406},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is used for the treatment of syphilis?","answers":[{"option":"Acyclovir","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":true}],"id":407},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following leads to the activation of the coagulation cascade in SIRS?","answers":[{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue factor","bool":true},{"option":"Interferon alpha","bool":false},{"option":"IL-1 and IL-6","bool":false}],"id":408},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is used for giardiasis and gives rise to metallic taste as its side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium stibogluconate","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false}],"id":409},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 34-year-old presents with abdominal pain, bloating, nausea, and vomiting for the past few days. A complete blood count reveals eosinophilia. Small bowel obstruction is present. A nasogastric (NG) tube is inserted. Which of the following drugs is the most appropriate?","answers":[{"option":"Mebendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":false},{"option":"Piperazine","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false}],"id":410},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of ciprofloxacin?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of dihydrofolate reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of topoisomerase I","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of topoisomerase IV","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibition of transpeptidase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibitor of cell wall synthesis","bool":false}],"id":411},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A man with a known case of HIV presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, weight loss, and fatigue. He is diagnosed with the case of mycobacterium avium complex. What is the treatment used for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Rifabutin as it prevents dissemination","bool":false},{"option":"Clarithromycin, rifabutin and ethambutol","bool":true},{"option":"Amphotericin B","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole","bool":false},{"option":"Azithromycin and clarithromycin","bool":false}],"id":412},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the best treatment for hydatid cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole and praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"PAIR and albendazole","bool":true},{"option":"Albendazole 400 mg for 3 months","bool":false},{"option":"Cyst resection","bool":false},{"option":"PAIR therapy","bool":false}],"id":413},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the most common non-inflammatory diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false}],"id":414},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following causes bloody diarrhea?","answers":[{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella","bool":true},{"option":"Vibrio cholera","bool":false},{"option":"Proteus mirabilis","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false}],"id":415},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Megaloblastic anemia caused by pyrimethamine can be reversed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cyanocobalamin","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha tocopherol","bool":false},{"option":"Leucovorin","bool":true},{"option":"Riboflavin","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false}],"id":416},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice in a patient who has foul-smelling diarrhea along with nausea, vomiting, and abdominal pain?","answers":[{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Metronidazole","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Clindamycin","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false}],"id":417},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"ELISA done for an HIV patient is stored for how many days?","answers":[{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4°C for 3 day upto 7 days","bool":true},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4°C for 4 day upto 8 days","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4°C for 2 day upto 6 days","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4°C for 1 day upto 5 days","bool":false},{"option":"10 ml blood at temperature 4°C for 5 day upto 9 days","bool":false}],"id":418},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Unilocular cyst seen in brain CT is a characteristic of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Enterococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus","bool":true}],"id":419},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"According to  Integrated Management of Neonatal & Childhood Illness (IMNCI), which of the following is the danger sign?","answers":[{"option":"Abnormal behavior","bool":false},{"option":"High grade fever","bool":false},{"option":"Convulsing now","bool":true},{"option":"Uprolling of eyes","bool":false},{"option":"Froth from mouth","bool":false}],"id":420},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the mechanism of action of maraviroc?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of glycoprotein 16","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive inhibition of HIV polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Integrase transfer strand inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Fusion of virion to T cell","bool":true}],"id":421},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which glycoproteins (gp) are used by the HIV to gain entry inside the cell?","answers":[{"option":"gp 120 and gp 12","bool":false},{"option":"gp 24 and gp 17","bool":false},{"option":"gp 160 and gp 41","bool":false},{"option":"gp 24 and gp 120","bool":false},{"option":"gp 120 and gp 41","bool":true}],"id":422},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the term used for the disease whose number of cases are occurring infrequently, haphazardly, and at different times and places?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperendemic","bool":false},{"option":"Sporadic","bool":true},{"option":"Endemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false}],"id":423},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A female patient presents to the gynecology department with a complaint of vaginal discharge. What is the non-infectious cause of vaginal discharge?","answers":[{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Chemical irritants","bool":true}],"id":424},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the gold standard test for salmonella typhi?","answers":[{"option":"Typhi dot test","bool":false},{"option":"Widal test","bool":false},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true},{"option":"Stool culture","bool":false}],"id":425},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following test is used to measure the efficacy of highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART)?","answers":[{"option":"CD3 count","bool":false},{"option":"p24 levels","bool":false},{"option":"CD24 count","bool":false},{"option":"p40 levels","bool":false},{"option":"Viral RNA","bool":true}],"id":426},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A patient presents to the emergency room with a cough, runny nose, and red eyes. On examination, koplik spots are found in the buccal mucosa. What is the patient suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false}],"id":427},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A child presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, fatigue, and severe itching in the rash. On examination, the papulovesicular rash is seen on the child's trunk and extremities. Which stain or smear can be used for the diagnosis of the organism involved?","answers":[{"option":"Gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Methylene blue","bool":false},{"option":"Tzanck smear","bool":true},{"option":"Giemsa stain","bool":false},{"option":"Ethanol","bool":false}],"id":428},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Strawberry cervix is seen in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false}],"id":429},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Zidovudine belongs to which class of group?","answers":[{"option":"Protease inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleotide reverse transcriptase inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"Non-nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Integrase inhibitor","bool":false}],"id":430},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Dying deposition has more weightage than dying declaration due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"It is taken under oath","bool":false},{"option":"Magistrate time is precious","bool":false},{"option":"It is recorded by magistrate","bool":false},{"option":"Given in the presence of accused","bool":true},{"option":"Remain valid after recovery","bool":false}],"id":431},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A patient has a positive test for salmonella typhi. Which disease is he suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Rabies","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false}],"id":432},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What should be the target central venous pressure (CVP) in sepsis?","answers":[{"option":"10-15 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"8-12 mm Hg","bool":true},{"option":"1-5 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"6-10 mm Hg","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 12 mm Hg","bool":false}],"id":433},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the drug of choice for vaginal candidiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Flucytosine","bool":false},{"option":"Cystatin","bool":false},{"option":"Fluconazole","bool":true},{"option":"Nystatin","bool":false},{"option":"Miconazole","bool":false}],"id":434},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"The CBC report of dengue hemorrhagic fever will show which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Neutropenia and leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Leukopenia and thrombocytopenia","bool":true},{"option":"Neutropenia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukopenia","bool":false}],"id":435},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"What is the drug of choice for visceral leishmaniasis?","answers":[{"option":"Praziquantel","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrantel pamoate","bool":false},{"option":"Liposomal amphotericin B","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium stibogluconate","bool":true}],"id":436},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which enzyme is required to make double-stranded DNA?","answers":[{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":true}],"id":437},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A patient presents to the gynecology department with a lesion in a genital area. On examination, it is found to be a sexually transmitted genital ulcerative disease in which irregular margins of a lesion are seen. The patient is also seen to have tender lymphadenopathy and diagnosis of chancroid is made. Chancroid is caused by which organism?","answers":[{"option":"Lactobacillus","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus ducreyi","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":438},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 2.5-year-old child is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of vomiting and loose stools for the past 2 days. On examination, no sunken eyes were found and the skin turgor test is normal. What is the appropriate management for this child?","answers":[{"option":"Ringer's lactate","bool":false},{"option":"5% dextrose","bool":true},{"option":"1/5 normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"1/2 normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"1/3 normal saline","bool":false}],"id":439},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A child is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of fever, and swelling in the jaw. The mother further adds the swelling is painful when the child drinks citrus fruit juices. On examination, swelling is noticed to be of parotid gland enlargement. What is the child suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":true},{"option":"Measles","bool":false}],"id":440},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is the likely cause of pneumonia in a patient who previously had a splenectomy?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus auerus","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false}],"id":441},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A swimmer developed diarrhea and abdominal cramping after the swimming competition. Which organism is the cause of his symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Trichomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":false},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false}],"id":442},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 20-year-old boy presents to the outpatient department with a complaint of fever after returning from his trip. The doctor prescribed him chloroquine. Which other drug should also be prescribed to him?","answers":[{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Co-trimoxazole","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Proguanil","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true}],"id":443},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A girl presents to the outpatient department with lethargy and an ulcer in her right foot. Her laboratory results show hemoglobin 6 mg/dL. What is the cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":false},{"option":"Ascaris lumbricoide","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":false},{"option":"Strongyloides stercoralis","bool":false},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":true}],"id":444},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A teenager is hospitalized with a history of a dog bite 2 weeks ago. He is found to be anxious, irritable, and drooling at the mouth. What is the appropriate treatment for him?","answers":[{"option":"Pass a nasogastric tube for feeding and medications","bool":false},{"option":"Provide a comfort care in a quiet environment","bool":true},{"option":"Empiric antibiotic therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Start him on ribavirin therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Pass an endotracheal tube for ventilation","bool":false}],"id":445},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A patient with a history of AIDs and tuberculosis 2 years back is admitted for the surgery of appendicitis. What precautions should be taken?","answers":[{"option":"Single ward with respiratory precautions","bool":true},{"option":"Single ward with contact precautions","bool":false},{"option":"General ward with standard precautions","bool":false},{"option":"General ward with contact precautions","bool":false},{"option":"Single ward with standard precautions","bool":false}],"id":446},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 26-year-old, pregnant woman is diagnosed with gonorrhea. There is a previous history of anaphylactic shock on the administration of amoxicillin. Which of the following drugs is given as a single dose?","answers":[{"option":"Cefixime","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Spectinomycin","bool":true}],"id":447},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following drugs will be added to the gonorrhea treatment regimen for the prevention of chlamydia?","answers":[{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":true},{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Spectinomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Cefexime","bool":false}],"id":448},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is gold standard for the diagnosis of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Blood film for microscopic examination of the parasite","bool":true},{"option":"Immunochromatographic rapid diagnostic tests (RDTs) for malarial antigens","bool":false},{"option":"Administration of chloroquine for sensitivity analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to detect plasmodium DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid screening card agglutination test for antibody detection","bool":false}],"id":449},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following enzymes forms dsDNA from ssRNA?","answers":[{"option":"Protease","bool":false},{"option":"Integrase","bool":false},{"option":"Endonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Ribonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":true}],"id":450},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"Which of the following is used routinely in clinics for the diagnosis of malaria?","answers":[{"option":"Immunochromatographic rapid diagnostic tests (RDTs) for malarial antigens","bool":true},{"option":"Administration of chloroquine for sensitivity analysis","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction (PCR) to detect plasmodium DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid screening card agglutination test for antibody detection","bool":false},{"option":"Blood film for microscopic examination of the parasite","bool":false}],"id":451},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2021"],"question":"A 29-year-old man presents with complaints of fever, which was initially low-grade and then became high-grade, headache, and abdominal discomfort. His vitals showed blood pressure 180/100 mmHg, and a pulse of 65 beats/min. What is the most likely cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}],"id":452},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old female presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of fever on alternate days, documented to be 103-104 °F, along with sweating and chills. She also had malaise, vomiting, weakness, muscle pain, and headache. She was pale and had a palpable spleen on examination. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":true},{"option":"Amoebiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Trypanosomiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid fever","bool":false}],"id":453},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 7-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of fever and vesicular rashes all over the body. The vesicles appear in bunches and some are in the healing phase. There is a history of sore throat and cough too. What is the long-term complication of the condition at a later age?","answers":[{"option":"Zoster/shingles","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false}],"id":454},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 14-year-old girl presents to the clinic with a complaint of a hypopigmented patch on her face. On examination, it is a well-demarcated area of skin that does not respond to pain stimuli. How is the condition diagnosed?","answers":[{"option":"Acid-fast staining","bool":true},{"option":"India ink staining","bool":false},{"option":"Darkfield staining","bool":false},{"option":"Modified acid-fast staining","bool":false},{"option":"Gram staining","bool":false}],"id":455},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 6-day-old neonate is brought to the pediatric emergency with a history of fits and refusal to take feed. The fits are more severe on exposure to light and excessive sound. The neonate was delivered at home. What is the causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillus anthracis","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false}],"id":456},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Salmonella typhi is transmitted by the orofecal route and is the causative agent of typhoid fever. What is the primary site of infection?","answers":[{"option":"Mononuclear phagocytic cells in the liver and spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Mononuclear phagocytic cells in the liver and Peyer's patches","bool":true},{"option":"Mononuclear phagocytic cells in the spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Mononuclear phagocytic cells in the large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Mononuclear phagocytic cells in the liver","bool":false}],"id":457},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Shigella dysenteriae causes fever, abdominal pain, and bloody diarrhea in humans. The infection is due to the release of Shiga toxin, which promotes tissue invasion in the large intestine. What is another name for Shiga toxin?","answers":[{"option":"Neurotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxin","bool":true},{"option":"Cytotoxin","bool":false},{"option":"Exotoxin","bool":false}],"id":458},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 25-year-old fisherman presented to the outpatient department with complaints of abdominal discomfort and diarrhea. His complete blood picture showed megaloblastic anemia and his stool had numerous oval operculated brown eggs. Which parasite is the cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Taenia saginata","bool":false},{"option":"Diphyllobothrium latum","bool":true},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Ancylostoma duodenale","bool":false}],"id":459},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 15-year-old boy presented to the outpatient department with fever, rash, and conjunctivitis. The rash appeared first on the face and then spread to the extremities including the palms and soles. Which viral infection is the boy suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Varicella","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes","bool":false}],"id":460},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 45-year-old man presented to the outpatient department with fever, constipation, and abdominal tenderness. Blood culture showed growth of non-lactose fermenting (colorless) gram-negative bacteria on MacConkey's agar and the production of hydrogen sulfide gas on TSI agar. What is the probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Enterocolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid fever","bool":true},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false}],"id":461},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old female presented with fever, chills, sweating, weakness, and headache, presumptively diagnosed as 'viral syndrome'. The patient's condition later deteriorated with altered level of consciousness, severe anemia, renal failure, and multisystem failure. Blood sample investigation showed malarial parasite. Crescent or sausage (banana) shaped gametocytes are a characteristic of which plasmodium species?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false}],"id":462},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) can frequently be observed in patients with severe inflammatory response and has a poor prognosis. Coagulation pathway activation leads to small vessels occlusion leading to various organ failure symptoms. Which of the following laboratory tests is used for evidence of DIC?","answers":[{"option":"Platelet count","bool":false},{"option":"Erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR)","bool":false},{"option":"Serum calcitonin","bool":false},{"option":"C-reactive protein","bool":false},{"option":"D-dimer","bool":true}],"id":463},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) attacks the immune system and if untreated, can cause acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS). HIV has several structural and non-structural proteins that play a role in infectivity. Which of the following is a structural gene of HIV?","answers":[{"option":"Nef","bool":false},{"option":"Gag","bool":true},{"option":"Vif","bool":false},{"option":"Tat","bool":false},{"option":"Rev","bool":false}],"id":464},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following antiviral drugs inhibits the synthesis of viral DNA?","answers":[{"option":"Amantadine","bool":false},{"option":"Acyclovir","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Saquinavir","bool":false},{"option":"Interferon","bool":false}],"id":465},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct about the mechanism of action of mebendazole?","answers":[{"option":"Blocks acetylcholine transmission at the myoneural junction resulting in paralysis of helminths.","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits oxidative phosphorylation in some species of helminths.","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits microtubule synthesis in helminths and causes irreversible impairment of glucose uptake.","bool":true},{"option":"Increases cell membrane permeability for calcium ions, resulting in paralysis, dislodgement, and death of helminths.","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":466},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which drug is the most effective in treating systemic fungal infections in patients with acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)?","answers":[{"option":"Itraconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Flucytosine","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Amphotericin B","bool":true},{"option":"Griseofulvin","bool":false}],"id":467},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which antimalarial drug can cause blackwater fever?","answers":[{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyremethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemisinin","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine","bool":true},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false}],"id":468},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which antimalarial drug is used for causal prophylaxis?","answers":[{"option":"Quinidine","bool":false},{"option":"Amodiaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrimethamine","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":true}],"id":469},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is/are an unwanted effect(s) of aminoglycosides?","answers":[{"option":"Dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"Pancytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Ototoxicity, nephrotoxicity","bool":true},{"option":"Hepatotoxicity","bool":false},{"option":"Irritation of gastrointestinal mucosa","bool":false}],"id":470},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which antibiotic is safe to use for respiratory tract infections during the first trimester of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoroquinolones","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":true}],"id":471},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which antibiotic can cause grey baby syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporin","bool":false},{"option":"Aminoglycosides","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true}],"id":472},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which drug is the first line agent in the treatment of syphilis?","answers":[{"option":"Macrolides","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalosporin","bool":false},{"option":"Amphotericin B","bool":false},{"option":"Benzathine penicillin G","bool":true},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false}],"id":473},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is another name for visceral leishmaniasis?","answers":[{"option":"Cyclosporiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptosporidiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Kala-azar","bool":true},{"option":"Mucocutaneous leishmaniasis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":474},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which test is helpful in the diagnosis of giardiasis?","answers":[{"option":"Stool for occult blood","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"String test","bool":true},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false},{"option":"Urine culture","bool":false}],"id":475},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Human cysticercosis is acquired by the ingestion of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aspergillosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sporotrichosis","bool":false},{"option":"Echinococcus granulosus","bool":false},{"option":"Taenia solium","bool":true},{"option":"Cryptococcosis","bool":false}],"id":476},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Ova of Schistosoma haematobium can be detected in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ascitic fluid","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Urine","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":false}],"id":477},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 45-year-old patient presents with right-sided focal fits. History reveals that he is an AIDS (acquired immunodeficiency syndrome) patient. Magnetic resonance imaging shows multiple ring-enhancing lesions in the cortical grey-white matter of the brain. What is the cause of fits?","answers":[{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"CNS toxoplasmosis","bool":true},{"option":"Peripheral neuropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive multifocal leukoencephalopathy","bool":false}],"id":478},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 50-year-old male HIV patient is being evaluated for AIDS-defining diseases. Which of the following is not an AIDS-defining illness?","answers":[{"option":"Oral candidiasis","bool":true},{"option":"CMV retinitis","bool":false},{"option":"Kaposi sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jiroveci pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Esophageal candidiasis","bool":false}],"id":479},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 50-year-old female sustained injury from rusty metal on her right finger while cleaning. She is cautious and seeks emergency treatment. You washed her wound with normal saline and dressed it. Which infection is she at risk of acquiring?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true},{"option":"Clostridium sordelli","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false}],"id":480},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 25-year-old male had a sexual contact with a commercial sex worker during his business trip to UAE. He developed a painless ulcer at the penile shaft after one week. What investigation will diagnose the genital ulcer?","answers":[{"option":"RPR with titer","bool":false},{"option":"Darkfield microscopy on genital ulcer","bool":true},{"option":"HSV PCR of blood","bool":false},{"option":"Tzank smear on tissue biopsy from the ulcer","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleic acid amplification test (NAAT)","bool":false}],"id":481},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Faisal experienced a car accident which caused him multiple injuries on the face. What are injuries on the face termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Daman","bool":false},{"option":"Ghair jaiffah","bool":false},{"option":"Jaiffah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah","bool":true},{"option":"Jurh","bool":false}],"id":482},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"During a police encounter, an armed robber shot the policeman in his abdomen. What is this penetrating injury termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Jaiffah","bool":true},{"option":"Jurh","bool":false},{"option":"Ghair jaiffah","bool":false},{"option":"Shajjah","bool":false},{"option":"Daman","bool":false}],"id":483},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 20-year-old came to you with the complaint of abdominal pain and vomiting. What type of consent will you take before starting physical examination?","answers":[{"option":"Implied","bool":true},{"option":"Blanket","bool":false},{"option":"Expressed","bool":false},{"option":"Written","bool":false},{"option":"Informed","bool":false}],"id":484},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"An injured person presented to the emergency with a broken leg and internal fixation was done by a doctor in the operation theatre. The patient was advised to rest for two weeks but he started walking in a couple of days and developed misalignment of the fractured bone. The given explanation best corresponds to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Res ipsa loquitor","bool":false},{"option":"Vicarious liability","bool":false},{"option":"Contributary negligence","bool":true},{"option":"Novus actus interveniens","bool":false},{"option":"Therapeutic misadventure","bool":false}],"id":485},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"An 8-year-old child suffered from a minor injury during a picnic off from home. The teacher gave the consent for the treatment because of the absence of parents/guardians of the child. Which doctrine is applied here?","answers":[{"option":"Doctrine of informed consent","bool":false},{"option":"Doctrine of therapeutic privilege","bool":false},{"option":"Doctrine of loco parentis","bool":true},{"option":"Doctrine of full disclosure","bool":false},{"option":"Doctrine of emergency","bool":false}],"id":486},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 30-year-old married man is suffering from scabies. The doctor who treated his illness disclosed the information to his wife. What is this an example of?","answers":[{"option":"Professional secrecy","bool":false},{"option":"Interest of state","bool":false},{"option":"Community risk","bool":false},{"option":"Privileged communication","bool":true},{"option":"Therapeutic privilege","bool":false}],"id":487},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 4-year-old boy came to the outpatient department with fever for fifteen days. On examination, he was lethargic and pale, temperature was 101 °F, heart rate was 110 beats/min, and respiratory rate was 30 breaths/min. Abdominal examination showed hepatosplenomegaly. Rest of the examination was unremarkable. What is the most appropriate investigation to reach the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"Urine detailed report","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow culture","bool":false},{"option":"Urine culture","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":true}],"id":488},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 15-month-old girl was brought to the outpatient department with the complaint of high-grade fever and runny nose since three days. On examination, her temperature was 102 °F, heart rate was 120 beats/min, and respiratory rate was 35 breaths/min. She had a maculopapular rash all over the body, purulent discharge from the eyes, and oral thrush. Rest of the examination was unremarkable. What is the most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Nystatin oral drops","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol eye ointment","bool":false},{"option":"Oral vitamin A","bool":true},{"option":"Paracetamol syrup","bool":false},{"option":"Oral antibiotic","bool":false}],"id":489},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 23-year-old medical student develops nausea, vomiting, abdominal pain, and diarrhea after eating street food. Her complete blood count shows hemoglobin 12.8 g/dL, white blood cells 4200/mm³, erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) 35 mm/h, and low platelet count (98000/μL). What is the most predominant feature of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Patient can present with bloody diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Patient can present with rose red spots","bool":false},{"option":"Disease can be transmitted by contact","bool":false},{"option":"Patient has petechia on the arms and legs","bool":false},{"option":"Can result in a chronic carrier state","bool":false}],"id":490},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 45-year-old male is suffering from high-grade fever, severe body ache, and bleeding from the nose and mouth since the last 2 days. He consulted his general physician but the prescribed medicines did not give any relief. He works as a butcher and handles alive animals. His complete blood count shows hemoglobin 14.5 g/dL, white blood cells 1200/mm³, platelet count 37000/mm³. What is the best treatment option for him?","answers":[{"option":"Transfusion of platelet mega units","bool":false},{"option":"IV domperidone or any other prokinetic agent","bool":false},{"option":"IV normal saline","bool":false},{"option":"IV paracetamol as per need","bool":false},{"option":"IV antibiotics to prevent bacterial infection","bool":true}],"id":491},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 45-year-old female had fever and chills. Malarial parasite was positive on MP-ICT. She was treated with artemisinin based combination therapy. She went to donate blood after one session. The blood bank refused donation because she had gametocytes on peripheral smear. She is worried and wants a retreatment. What should be the next step of management?","answers":[{"option":"Needs long term prophylaxis to clear the gametocytes","bool":false},{"option":"A different antimalarial drug should be used","bool":false},{"option":"No need for treatment","bool":false},{"option":"Repeat course of artemisinin based combination therapy (ACT)","bool":true},{"option":"Repeat peripheral smear from well reputed laboratory","bool":false}],"id":492},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is a complication of Entamoeba histolytica?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cysticercosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hydatid cyst disease","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Amebic abscess","bool":true}],"id":493},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A medical worker accidentally gets pricked by a needle used on an HIV-positive patient. What is the risk percentage of him getting an HIV infection?","answers":[{"option":"0.1%","bool":false},{"option":"0.3%","bool":true},{"option":"0.05%","bool":false},{"option":"0.5%","bool":false},{"option":"0.67%","bool":false}],"id":494},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A man falls in the washroom and later presents with a high-grade fever. The doctor suspects that he has chronic inflammation. Which of the following are the dominant cells of chronic inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false}],"id":495},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) has structural genes and functional genes. Which of the following is a structural gene in HIV?","answers":[{"option":"pol","bool":true},{"option":"vif","bool":false},{"option":"rev","bool":false},{"option":"tat","bool":false},{"option":"nef","bool":false}],"id":496},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Penicillin should not be administered via which of the following routes?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous route","bool":false},{"option":"Intraperitoneal route","bool":false},{"option":"Intra-articular route","bool":false},{"option":"Intrathecal route","bool":true},{"option":"Intramuscular route","bool":false}],"id":497},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is a non-infectious cause of vaginal discharge?","answers":[{"option":"Chemical irritants","bool":true},{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":498},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole is used to treat which of the following infections in HIV-positive patients?","answers":[{"option":"Oral candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jirovecii pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Crytoccocal meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Toxoplasmosis","bool":false}],"id":499},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A medical officer detects an HIV (human immunodeficiency virus) positive case in the blood bank and searches for the sexual partner of the donor to prevent and treat the disease in the partner. Which process is described here?","answers":[{"option":"HIV contact tracing","bool":true},{"option":"HIV screening","bool":false},{"option":"HIV prophylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"HIV primary prevention","bool":false},{"option":"HIV case detection","bool":false}],"id":500},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A person, while traveling, carries a disease with him from an area where it is highly prevalent, to a place in which it does not normally occur. Which of the following terms is used for it?","answers":[{"option":"Hyper epidemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":false},{"option":"Exotic","bool":true},{"option":"Holo endemic","bool":false}],"id":501},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A young female presents to the outpatient department with greenish, foul-smelling vaginal discharge. A wet mount shows pear-shaped trophozoites with a jerky motion. Which of the following is the most likely organism involved?","answers":[{"option":"Entamaoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":true}],"id":502},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"In an AIDS (acquired immune deficiency syndrome) patient, purplish, non-blanching nodules appear in the lower extremities. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Molluscum contagiosum","bool":false},{"option":"Bacillary angiomatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Kaposi's sarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Pyogenic granulomas","bool":false}],"id":503},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient starts having diarrhea after taking antibiotics during his hospital stay. Which organism is most likely involved?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":true}],"id":504},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following organisms can cause cervical cancer and anogenital warts known as condylomata acuminata?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false},{"option":"Human papilloma virus","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":505},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following infections in sexually active women does not cause vaginal discharge?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"HIV (human immunodeficiency virus)","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcal/staphylococcal infections","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false}],"id":506},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with abdominal pain, relative bradycardia, and a fever that started as low-grade but has been persistently increasing for days. He also has salmon-colored spots on his trunk. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":true},{"option":"Roseola","bool":false}],"id":507},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient presents to the clinic with a high-grade fever, productive cough, and a runny nose with red eyes. He, later on, notices a maculopapular rash beginning to appear on his forehead. What is the patient most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":false},{"option":"Roseola","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false}],"id":508},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A child is brought to the clinic for having loose stools with a frequency of 20 per day. On examination, normal skin turgor and no sunken eyes are found. When water is offered, he drinks it eagerly. What is the classification according to IMNCI?","answers":[{"option":"Diarrhea with some dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea with mild dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea with no dehydration","bool":true},{"option":"Diarrhea with moderate dehydration","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea with severe dehydration","bool":false}],"id":509},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"What is the term used for diarrhea (with or without blood in stool) that starts acutely and occurs for at least 14 days?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Dysentry","bool":false},{"option":"Acute diarrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic diarrhea","bool":false}],"id":510},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following stages of the malarial parasite is liberated after the rupture of erythrocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Schizonts","bool":false},{"option":"Gametocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":true},{"option":"Trophozoite","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoites","bool":false}],"id":511},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A person having mucopurulent urethral discharge is diagnosed with gonorrhea. Which of the following will be shown on culture?","answers":[{"option":"Gram negative cocci in grape like cluster","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive cocci","bool":false},{"option":"Gram negative diplococci","bool":true},{"option":"Gram positive cocci in grape like cluster","bool":false},{"option":"Gram positive rods","bool":false}],"id":512},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A child is brought to the pediatrics clinic for evaluation of diarrhea. His systemic findings are unremarkable except that he has less weight and height for his age. It is found that he has malabsorption syndrome. What is the causative agent in this case?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterobius vermicularis","bool":false},{"option":"Giardia lamblia","bool":true},{"option":"Cryptosporidium hominis","bool":false}],"id":513},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient presents to the clinic with a complaint of bloody diarrhea. A sorbitol-negative strain of Escherichia coli is found to be the causative agent. Which of the following has caused this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Enteroaggregative E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterotoxigenic E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enteroinvasive E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"Enterohemorrhagic E. coli","bool":true},{"option":"Enteropathogenic E. coli","bool":false}],"id":514},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A person presents to the clinic with bloody diarrhea and is diagnosed with intestinal amebiasis caused by Entamoeba histolytica. Which of the following is true for this organism?","answers":[{"option":"Trophozoites have three nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Trophozoites contain ingested RBCs","bool":true},{"option":"Trophozoites have chromatin granules","bool":false},{"option":"Trophozoites contain marginated nucleolus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":515},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"An 18-year-old man is having conjunctival erythema with lacrimation and purulent discharge more prominent in the left eye. He consults his ophthalmologist who tells him that he is having follicular conjunctivitis and punctate keratitis. Giemsa stain shows cytoplasmic inclusions with no growth on culture with Gram stain. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Candida albicans","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":true},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":false},{"option":"Human papillomavirus","bool":false}],"id":516},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is used for the treatment of methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus?","answers":[{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Nafcillin","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin G","bool":false},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false}],"id":517},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following drugs is a protease inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Raltegravir","bool":false},{"option":"Stavudine","bool":false},{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Indinavir","bool":true},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":false}],"id":518},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A child presents with high-grade fever, runny nose, and cough. White lesions are found on the oral mucosa. What is the pathognomonic sign for measles?","answers":[{"option":"Koplik’s spots","bool":true},{"option":"Erythema nodosum","bool":false},{"option":"Vesicular lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Red spots","bool":false},{"option":"Umbilicated lesions","bool":false}],"id":519},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 28-year-old man has a fever, headache, and a rash present on his trunk and extremities with itching. On examinations, vesicles and papules of varying sizes are seen on his trunk and extremities and some are in the healing stage. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chicken pox","bool":true},{"option":"Roseola","bool":false},{"option":"Small pox","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false}],"id":520},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A woman is admitted for an elective/non-emergency procedure. Which type of consent should be taken before the operation?","answers":[{"option":"Written","bool":false},{"option":"Oral","bool":false},{"option":"Oral and expressed","bool":false},{"option":"Implied","bool":false},{"option":"Expressed and written","bool":true}],"id":521},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements is true about chloramphenicol?","answers":[{"option":"It is bactericidal","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits the 50S subunit of ribosomes","bool":true},{"option":"It is an antifungal drug","bool":false},{"option":"It is a narrow-spectrum antibiotic","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":522},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"An old man came with slowly progressive hypopigmented skin lesions on the chest and abdomen. He had a previous history of skin lesions that healed spontaneously. He also reported loss of sensation in some regions of his skin and thickened nerves. What stain will be used to visualize the causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Gram stain","bool":false},{"option":"Wright stain","bool":false},{"option":"Ziehl Neelsen stain","bool":true},{"option":"Giemsa stain","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":523},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient comes to the emergency department with a history of prolonged cough, fever, and chest infection. He is diagnosed with a case of tuberculosis after getting confirmation from the report of the biopsy. What is tuberculosis characterized by?","answers":[{"option":"Collection of serous fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Monocyte infiltration","bool":false},{"option":"Congested blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":true}],"id":524},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A blood culture shows the growth of non-lactose fermenting (colorless), gram-negative bacteria on MacConkey's agar and the production of hydrogen sulfide gas on TSI agar. Which of the following is the most likely organism?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":true},{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":525},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old male presents to the clinic with hypopigmented lesions on his limbs and back. He has been treated with antifungals but did not heal. He has also developed polyarthritis with edema. He has thick cutaneous nerves, radial, ulnar, and tibial nerves. The nerves are painful and tender. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Borderline tuberculoid leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline lepromatous leprosy","bool":false}],"id":526},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient had a hypopigmented skin lesion on one side, which progressed to multiple sites. Some of these lesions resolved on their own and then new lesions appeared. He also has anorexia, fever, and weight loss. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Borderline tuberculoid leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculoid leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Borderline lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromatous leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Mid-line leprosy","bool":false}],"id":527},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A female patient presents to the clinic with a complaint of purulent vaginal discharge. Gram staining of the discharge reveals gram-negative diplococci. What is the best treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":true},{"option":"Azithromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin G","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false}],"id":528},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 35-year-old diabetic patient presents to the outpatient department with complaints of fever associated with rigors and chills, and increased frequency of urine. She also complains of pain during micturition. Other systemic findings are unremarkable. What is the most accurate test for diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Urine DR/culture","bool":true},{"option":"Malarial antigen","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}],"id":529},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient presents to the clinic with complaints of cough and chest pain suggestive of pneumonia. He has had a splenectomy. Which of the following gram-positive organisms can be the causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumococcus","bool":true},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false}],"id":530},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following organisms is commonly responsible for causing watery diarrhea in less than 5-year-olds and results in more than 2 million hospital admissions annually?","answers":[{"option":"Shigella","bool":false},{"option":"Rotavirus","bool":true},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli","bool":false}],"id":531},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A man presents to the clinic with the complaint of a thick, yellow, mucoid, and purulent urethral discharge. He has had a new sexual partner for two weeks. Which infections would you consider in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Gonorrhea and Chlamydia","bool":true},{"option":"Trichomoniasis","bool":false}],"id":532},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient is brought to the clinic with the complaint of fever, cough, dyspnea, and cyanosis. He also has tachycardia and his blood pressure is 80/60 mmHg. On auscultation, crackles and decreased breath sounds can be heard in the right lower lobe. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Systemic infammatory response syndrome (SIRS)","bool":false},{"option":"Severe sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple organ dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":true}],"id":533},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"The coagulation cascade in systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS) is mediated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"IL1 and IL6","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue factor","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"C5a","bool":false}],"id":534},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following cells are found in the synovium of the joint in case of acute arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Dendritic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false}],"id":535},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following leads to the dilation of the arterioles and increased venous permeability?","answers":[{"option":"Histamine","bool":true},{"option":"Thromboxane A2","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene B4","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":536},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A 40-year-old male presents with dyspnea, cyanosis, and tachycardia. He is a chain smoker and there is a ventilation-perfusion mismatch on the V/Q scan. Which of the following lung complications can result as a result of systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS)?","answers":[{"option":"Lung infection","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)","bool":false},{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false}],"id":537},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following statements about interferon-α is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Toxicity includes bone marrow suppression","bool":false},{"option":"Indications include treatment of genital warts","bool":false},{"option":"Lamivudine interferes with its activity against hepatitis B","bool":true},{"option":"At the start of treatment, most patients experience flu like symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"It is used in the management of hepatitis C","bool":false}],"id":538},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is an important dose-dependent adverse effect of dapsone?","answers":[{"option":"Cirrhosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemolysis","bool":false},{"option":"Methemoglobinemia","bool":true},{"option":"Renal failure","bool":false}],"id":539},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following is a late complication of measles?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Subacute sclerosing panencephalitis","bool":true},{"option":"Measles encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":false}],"id":540},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A person, before going on a trip to a malaria-endemic area, takes prophylaxis for chloroquine-resistant falciparum malaria but nonetheless develops Plasmodium vivax malaria. Which of the following drugs did he most likely take?","answers":[{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"Atovaqoune","bool":false},{"option":"Mefloquine","bool":true},{"option":"Proguanil","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false}],"id":541},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"Which of the following antimalarial drugs acts as a blood schizonticide and a sporontocide?","answers":[{"option":"Quinine","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":true},{"option":"Artimisinin","bool":false},{"option":"Atovaquone","bool":false}],"id":542},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A housewife presents to the clinic with severe abdominal pain and diarrhea which started off as watery but now contains blood in it. Laboratory findings show leukocytes and red blood cells in the stool. She denies having eaten any undercooked food in the past week. Which of the following organisms is most likely involved?","answers":[{"option":"Helicobacter pylori","bool":false},{"option":"Salmonella species","bool":false},{"option":"Shigella species","bool":true},{"option":"Entamoeba histolytica","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}],"id":543},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"There is a patient with a clear indication of sepsis. He also has marked hypotension. What is the most appropriate management at this point?","answers":[{"option":"Persistent blood transfusions to keep his Hb at >10 g/dl","bool":false},{"option":"Give him a heavy dose of corticosteroids as soon as possible","bool":false},{"option":"Treat the patient with empirical antibiotics after culture and sensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Aggressive fluid resuscitation to keep central venous pressure 8-12 mm Hg","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}],"id":544},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A patient who was diagnosed with AIDS (acquired immune deficiency syndrome) and tuberculosis (TB) 2 years back is admitted for surgery for appendicitis. He is compliant with HIV medications. He completed anti-TB therapy and now his chest x-ray is clear with no pulmonary infiltrates and no bacteria in his sputum. What precautions should be taken?","answers":[{"option":"Single ward with contact precautions","bool":false},{"option":"Single ward with standard precautions","bool":false},{"option":"General ward with contact precautions","bool":false},{"option":"Single room with contact and airborne precautions","bool":false},{"option":"General ward with standard precautions","bool":true}],"id":545},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A health officer has taken up the challenge to eradicate HIV (human immunodeficiency virus). His team identified groups of high-risk individuals. Which of the following high-risk groups should be intervened first?","answers":[{"option":"Men having sex with men","bool":true},{"option":"Neonates","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnant women","bool":false},{"option":"Sex workers","bool":false},{"option":"Professional or paid blood donors","bool":false}],"id":546},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2022"],"question":"A man presents to the hospital with an altered level of consciousness two hours after falling in the washroom. He has pinpoint pupils with a pulse of 78 beats per minute, a blood pressure of 180/120 mmHg, and a fever of 107°F despite antipyretics. Sponging is also of no use. What is the most likely cause of fever?","answers":[{"option":"Encephalitis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":false}],"id":547},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"The district government of a certain city is trying to control a malaria epidemic. For this purpose, they want to initiate the strategy of vector control. They launch the distribution of insecticide-treated nets (ITNs) to households. Which of the following captures the other core intervention that must be used for effective vector control?","answers":[{"option":"Vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"Surveillance","bool":false},{"option":"Preventive chemotherapies","bool":false},{"option":"Indoor residual spraying (IRS)","bool":true},{"option":"Prophylaxis","bool":false}],"id":548},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A physician is interested in performing entomological testing on the mosquito which is an important vector for transmitting viral fevers in Pakistan. Which of the following mosquitoes is of interest to him?","answers":[{"option":"Anopheles stephensi","bool":false},{"option":"Aedes aegypti","bool":true},{"option":"Aedes triseriatus","bool":false},{"option":"Culiseta mosquito","bool":false},{"option":"Culex mosquito","bool":false}],"id":549},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A non-governmental organization working to control malaria in flood-affected areas of Pakistan seeks advice from a public health specialist regarding the control and elimination of malaria. Which one of the following options captures the most appropriate advice?","answers":[{"option":"Preventive chemotherapies","bool":false},{"option":"Vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"DDT spraying","bool":false},{"option":"Surveillance","bool":false},{"option":"Vector control","bool":true}],"id":550},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with a history of cough for more than three weeks, night sweats, loss of appetite, and fever. The physician advises a chest x-ray, sputum culture, and Zeihl-nelson staining of the sputum. He was diagnosed as a case of tuberculosis. Which one of the following is an identifying feature of tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Accumulation of macrophges","bool":false},{"option":"Constriction of blood vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Granuloma formation","bool":true},{"option":"Collection of serous fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Infiltration of monocytes","bool":false}],"id":551},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"The journey of leukocytes from the vessel lumen to the tissue is a multi-step process mediated and controlled by adhesion molecules and cytokines called chemokines. Which one of the following statements is correct regarding sequential phases?","answers":[{"option":"Adhesion, margination, and rolling to endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Margination, adhesion, and rolling to endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Margination inside the endothelium and vessel wall","bool":false},{"option":"Margination in a tissue towards a chemotactic stimulus","bool":false},{"option":"Rolling, margination, and adhesion to endothelium","bool":true}],"id":552},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 3-year-old unvaccinated girl is brought to the outpatient department with fever, cough, runny nose, and watery eyes for 3 days. On physical examination, there is a maculopapular rash on the face, neck, and trunk. Her elder sibling has a history of similar complaints from 1 week ago. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Varicella zoster","bool":false},{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Kawasaki diseases","bool":false}],"id":553},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 6-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of high-grade fever (102°F) for 4 days. On physical examination, the child is febrile with cropped vesicles on the trunk and scattered scabbed lesions. Which of the following infections is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Enterovirus virus","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus virus","bool":false},{"option":"Rubella virus","bool":false},{"option":"Measles virus","bool":false},{"option":"Varicella virus","bool":true}],"id":554},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 40-year-old female presents with complaints of purulent vaginal discharge and intermenstrual bleeding. Gram staining of endocervical screening revealed the presence of gram-negative diplococci. What would be the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Herpex simplex","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoeae","bool":true},{"option":"Hemophilus ducreyi","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydiae trachomatis","bool":false}],"id":555},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A young man presented to the emergency room with a history of high-grade fever\r\nassociated with chills and rigors. He lives in an area of poor sanitation, streets with stagnant water, insects, and mosquitoes. A complete blood count (CBC) examination of blood from the patient revealed distorted RBCs, double in size, and Schüffner's dots. What is the causative agent?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmodium knowlesi","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium falciparum","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium malariae","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmodium vivax","bool":true}],"id":556},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Once the fusion of HIV takes place with the host cell, viral RNA is released into the cytoplasm. Viral RNA is then used to synthesize dsDNA by which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Protease","bool":false},{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Reverse transcriptase","bool":true},{"option":"Integrase","bool":false}],"id":557},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"HIV uses a CD4⁺ molecule as a receptor, which is present in CD4⁺ cells such as T-lymphocytes, macrophages, monocytes, dendritic cells other and antigen-presenting cells. Virus entry into the human cell is mediated by which of the following proteins?","answers":[{"option":"Vpr","bool":false},{"option":"P24 antigen","bool":false},{"option":"Vif","bool":false},{"option":"gp120 and gp41","bool":true},{"option":"P9 gag","bool":false}],"id":558},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Malaria is an intermittent and remittent fever caused by a protozoan parasite that invades the red blood cells and is transmitted by mosquitoes in many tropical and subtropical regions. Anopheles mosquito takes a blood meal from humans and injects which of the forms of plasmodium parasite?","answers":[{"option":"Gametocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Merozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Shizont","bool":false},{"option":"Hypnozoites","bool":false},{"option":"Sporozoite","bool":true}],"id":559},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Balanced infection control practices (ICP) can save hospitals a considerable amount of money, e.g., an outbreak of GNR can be controlled effectively by hand hygiene rather than prescribing expensive antibiotics. \"The first requirement in a hospital is that it should do the sick no harm.\" Who said the above words?","answers":[{"option":"Willam","bool":false},{"option":"Florence Nightingale","bool":true},{"option":"Ogston","bool":false},{"option":"Colbrook","bool":false},{"option":"Lister","bool":false}],"id":560},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A young child presented to the outpatient department with a history of low-grade fever, loss of appetite, and lethargy. Blood culture is positive for Salmonella typhi. Salmonella typhi is transmitted by which of the following routes?","answers":[{"option":"Oral fecal route","bool":true},{"option":"Skin penetration","bool":false},{"option":"Inhalation","bool":false},{"option":"Sexual route","bool":false},{"option":"Blood transfusion","bool":false}],"id":561},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 24-year-old male patient presents with pain in his left knee and a burning sensation during urination. On examination, he has noticeable conjunctival inflammation. He denies any recent gastroenteritis but has had several sexual partners and has not always used protection. Which organism is most likely responsible for his presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":true},{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma genitalium","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoea","bool":false},{"option":"Trichomalis vaginalis","bool":false}],"id":562},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 33-year-old woman presents to the outpatient department with a three-day history of a white, fishy vaginal discharge. She has no history of sexually transmitted disease, post-coital bleeding, or dysuria. On speculum examination, there is a milky fluid in the posterior fornix but no signs of inflammation. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhoea","bool":false},{"option":"Donovanosis","bool":false},{"option":"Candidiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":true}],"id":563},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"What are the four rules of professional-patient relationships set forth and explained by Beauchamp and Childress?","answers":[{"option":"Respect for autonomy, non-maleficence, beneficence, and justice","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomy, non-maleficence, equality, and justice","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomy, privacy, respect, and confidentiality","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomy, privacy, respect, and secrecy","bool":false},{"option":"Veracity, privacy, beneficence, and non-maleficence","bool":false}],"id":564},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"What is the concept of justice in ethics?","answers":[{"option":"Taken as patients right to choose or refuse treatment","bool":false},{"option":"An obligation of the patient to the society","bool":false},{"option":"To keep the secrecy of patient","bool":false},{"option":"Health resources must be distributed according to the principals of equity","bool":true},{"option":"For medical professionals to do good for all patients under all circumstances","bool":false}],"id":565},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Regarding expressed oral consent, which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"It should be signed by both, doctor as well as patient","bool":false},{"option":"It is taken in minor procedures","bool":true},{"option":"It should be signed by the patient only","bool":false},{"option":"Only taken in emergencies","bool":false},{"option":"It is taken for unconscious patients","bool":false}],"id":566},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"In which of the following circumstances can confidentiality be breached?","answers":[{"option":"When lawyer need information","bool":false},{"option":"When financial resources are scarce and patient is not compliant","bool":false},{"option":"For a patient who requires invasive treatment","bool":false},{"option":"When a patient authorizes to do so","bool":true},{"option":"When the patient does not listen to the doctor","bool":false}],"id":567},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Transplantation terminology contains terms to describe the relationship of the graft donor to the graft recipient. Which of the following is the correct terminology for a graft between genetically non-identical members of the same species?","answers":[{"option":"Allogeneic graft","bool":true},{"option":"Autogenic graft","bool":false},{"option":"Xenogeneic graft","bool":false},{"option":"Halogenic graft","bool":false},{"option":"Isogeneic graft","bool":false}],"id":568},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"In a court of law, leading questions are permitted exclusively during cross-examination. What is the only other circumstance in which the prosecution can pose leading questions?","answers":[{"option":"Chemical examiner's testimony","bool":false},{"option":"Witness declared hostile","bool":true},{"option":"Re-examination","bool":false},{"option":"Volunteering a statement","bool":false},{"option":"Privileged communication","bool":false}],"id":569},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following terms describes all legal means that help a fact, the truth of which is submitted in judicial proceedings?","answers":[{"option":"Deposition","bool":false},{"option":"Summon","bool":false},{"option":"Evidence","bool":true},{"option":"Affidavit","bool":false},{"option":"Testimony","bool":false}],"id":570},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"An injured person with a broken leg was being transported to the hospital in an ambulance. At a signal crossing, suddenly another vehicle collided with the ambulance resulting in the death of the injured person. What legal principle or concept is most applicable to this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Res ipsa loquitur","bool":false},{"option":"Novus actus interveniens","bool":true},{"option":"Confounding negligence","bool":false},{"option":"Vicarious liability","bool":false},{"option":"Contributory negligence","bool":false}],"id":571},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"The parents presented a 3-year-old female child to the outpatient department with a one-week history of fever and cough, accompanied by conjunctivitis and coryza for the past three days. Notably, the child's elder brother experienced a similar condition characterized by a maculopapular rash all over his body two weeks ago. What is the likely problem with this child?","answers":[{"option":"Upper respiratory tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Viral conjunctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Lower respiratory tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":true}],"id":572},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"The parents brought a 10-year-old male child with a history of fever for 10 days. On examination, the child appears sick, febrile, and toxic. What is the gold standard test for diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Widal Test","bool":false},{"option":"Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR)","bool":false},{"option":"Blood culture and sensitivity","bool":true},{"option":"Typhi dot","bool":false},{"option":"Complete Blood Count (CBC)","bool":false}],"id":573},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is the first choice drug for the treatment of enteric fever?","answers":[{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftriaxone","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":false}],"id":574},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is the drug of choice for a cestode infestation?","answers":[{"option":"Carbamizapine","bool":false},{"option":"Ivermectin","bool":false},{"option":"Niclosamide","bool":false},{"option":"Albendazole","bool":false},{"option":"Praziquantal","bool":true}],"id":575},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following is a protease inhibitor used in combination for treatment of HIV?","answers":[{"option":"Efavirenz","bool":false},{"option":"Tenofovir","bool":false},{"option":"Etravirine","bool":false},{"option":"Raltegravir","bool":false},{"option":"Indinavir","bool":true}],"id":576},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which of the following statements is correct about anti-staphylococcal antibiotics?","answers":[{"option":"Are synthetic","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillinase-sensitive","bool":false},{"option":"Extended spectrum","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillinase-resistant","bool":true},{"option":"Broad spectrum","bool":false}],"id":577},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 27-year-old nursing mother is diagnosed as suffering from genital herpes. She has a history of this viral infection. Previously, she responded to a drug used topically. Which drug to be used orally is most likely to be prescribed at this time?","answers":[{"option":"Amantadine","bool":false},{"option":"Foscarnet","bool":false},{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":false},{"option":"Valacyclovir","bool":true},{"option":"Trifluridine","bool":false}],"id":578},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A patient with AIDS has a CD4 count of 45/µL. He is being maintained on a 3-drug regimen of indinavir, didanosine, and zidovudine. Which of the following drugs may cause an episode of acute pancreatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Zidovudine","bool":false},{"option":"Didanosine","bool":true},{"option":"Acyclovir","bool":false},{"option":"Ketoconazole","bool":false},{"option":"Ritonavir","bool":false}],"id":579},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A premature neonate suffered respiratory distress and was given an antibiotic 100 mg/kg/day orally. Over the next two days, his condition worsened. He became dull, stopped feeding, and developed abdominal distention, and an ashen grey appearance. Which is the most likely antibiotic given to him?","answers":[{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":true},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Minocycline","bool":false}],"id":580},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"An 8-year-old child presented with brownish discolored and deformed anterior teeth. He has a history of taking an antibiotic about 4 years earlier. Which antibiotic could be responsible for the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":false},{"option":"Gentamicin","bool":false},{"option":"Ampicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Tetracycline","bool":true},{"option":"Erythromycin","bool":false}],"id":581},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which enzymes are the target for the quinolone antibacterial agents?","answers":[{"option":"Transpeptidases","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclases","bool":false},{"option":"Kinases","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerases","bool":true},{"option":"Proteases","bool":false}],"id":582},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"Which fluoroquinolone is highly active against Mycobacterium leprae and is being used in alternative multidrug therapy regimens?","answers":[{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Levofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Ofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"Lomefloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Norfloxacin","bool":false}],"id":583},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 35-year-old male presented to the outpatient department with a prolonged history of fever and weight loss. On clinical examination, there is lymphadenopathy and hepatosplenomegaly. Complete blood count (CBC) shows pancytopenia. He is suspected of visceral leishmaniasis. Which of the following investigations is used for definitive diagnosis of visceral leishmaniasis?","answers":[{"option":"Molecular test","bool":false},{"option":"Serology","bool":false},{"option":"Antigen based rapid test","bool":false},{"option":"Identification of amastigote in macrophages in tissue sample","bool":true},{"option":"Blood culture","bool":false}],"id":584},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 16-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with a three-day history of high-grade fever, flu, itchy red eyes, and rashes all over the body. On examination, the physician found Kolpik spots in the oral cavity and a maculopapular rash scattered all over the body. The most likely diagnosis will be?","answers":[{"option":"Rubella","bool":false},{"option":"Mumps","bool":false},{"option":"Measles","bool":true},{"option":"Chickenpox","bool":false},{"option":"Atopic dermatitis","bool":false}],"id":585},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 50-year-old female while cleaning her home sustained a rusty metal injury on her right finger. She is very cautious and came to seek treatment at the emergency department. You have washed her wound with normal saline and dressed it. Which of the following infections she is at risk of acquiring?","answers":[{"option":"Clostridium sordelli","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringens","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium tetani","bool":true}],"id":586},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 20-year-old college student presented to the medical specialist with complaints of fever, extra-orbital pain, and fatigue for one week. On examination, the patient is febrile and has a macular skin rash. The lab results reveal a Hb of 11 g/dl, a TLC of 3500 cells/dl, a platelet count of 50,000, and an increased hematocrit. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow fever","bool":false},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":true},{"option":"Idiopathic thrombocytopenic purpura","bool":false},{"option":"Leptospira","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":false}],"id":587},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 35-year-old man presented to the skin specialist with complaints of skin lesions on his face and arms for six months. The lesions are hypopigmented and lack sensation. On examination, the skin over the brows and ears has thickened, and there are nodules on the face. He was diagnosed as having leprosy. Which of the following statements is correct?","answers":[{"option":"There is no role for cell-mediated immunity, but granulomas are usually absent","bool":false},{"option":"Lepromin skin testing is positive in lepromatous types of leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Its clinical presentation is not classical","bool":false},{"option":"The lepromin skin test is positive in the tuberculoid type of leprosy","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculin skin test is positive for any type of leprosy","bool":false}],"id":588},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 19-year-old woman presented to the emergency department after complaining of abdominal pain, nausea, and vomiting for 2 hours. Her abdominal pain is sudden, and she has no history of fever or diarrhea. She had taken fried rice, grilled chicken, and vegetables for lunch five hours before at a local restaurant. What is the most likely mechanism responsible for the symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial invasion of the small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Malabsorption by bacterial overgrowth","bool":false},{"option":"Proliferation with subsequent production of toxins by bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial invasion of the large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Ingestion of preformed toxins","bool":true}],"id":589},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 36-year-old man presented to the emergency room with complaints of fever and mild abdominal pain for 3 days. On examination, he is febrile (103°F) with jaundice and a palpable spleen. Plasmodium falciparum trophozoites are visible in the peripheral film. In cases of uncomplicated falciparum malaria, which treatment is recommended?","answers":[{"option":"Artemether plus lumifantrine","bool":true},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Artemether plus proguanil","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Quinine and doxycycline","bool":false}],"id":590},{"info":["3rd-year/infectious/compiled","3rd-year/infectious/2023"],"question":"A 24-year-old man from Baluchistan presented to the dermatology clinic complaining of an erythematous nodule in his right arm that had been bothering him for a month. There are no such lesions located on the ears, lips, or oral mucosa. The systemic review was unremarkable. The histopathology of the lesion shows granulomatous inflammation in the dermis and peripherally located amastigotes. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Visceral leishmaniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Cutaneous leishmaniasis","bool":true},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Mucocutaneous leprosy","bool":false}],"id":591}]
export default arr